You are an obsession. I cannot sleep.
# You are an obsession. I cannot sleep. #
I am your possession. Unopened at your feet.
# I am your possession. Unopened at your feet. #
There's no balance, no equality.
# There's no balance, no equality. #
Be still, I will not accept defeat.
# Be still, I will not accept defeat. #
I will have you, Yes I will have you.
# I will have you, Yes I will have you. #
I will find a way and I will have you.
# I will find a way and I will have you. #
Like a butterfly, a wild butterfly.
# Like a butterfly, a wild butterfly. #
I will collect you and capture you.
# I will collect you and capture you. #
I don't think this is goth night.
فکر نکنم امشب شب گت باشه
This place sucks!
اينجا مزخرفه
Indeed!
واقعا
Who do you want me to be to make you sleep with me?
مي خواي من کي باشم برات تا بياي باهام بخوابي
I'm going to the bathroom.
مي رم به حموم
There's an idea for a poem I want to write!
اين يه ايده است براي شعري که مي خوام بگم
Who do you want me to be to make you sleep with me?
مي خواي من کي باشم برات تا بياي باهام بخوابي
Hey! Watch it, fat ass!
هي مواظب باش گنده
#I need you, I need you, by sun or candlelight
من مي خوامت من مي خوامت چه با خورشيد يا نور شمع
You protest. You want to leave
تو اعتراض مي کني مي خواي بري
Stay. There's no alternative
بمون هيچ راهي نيست
Your face appears again. I see your beauty there
اگه چهره ات دوباره معلوم بشه من دوباره زيبايي ات رو مي بينم
But I see danger, stranger beware.
ولي خطر مي بينم غريبه مواظب باش
A circumstance in your naked dreams.
يه شرايطي در روياهاي عريانت
Your affection is not what it seems.
عکس العمل تو اون چيزي نيست که بنظر مي رسه
You are an obsession. You're my obsession.
# You are an obsession. You're my obsession. #
What do you want me to be to make you sleep with me?
# What do you want me to be to make you sleep with me? #
You are an obsession. You're my obsession.
# You are an obsession. You're my obsession. #
What do you want me to be to make you sleep with me?
# What do you want me to be to make you sleep with me? #
I want to leave, I don't belong here.
مي خوام برم اينجا جاي من نيست
It's fun cause we're together.
خوش مي گذره چون با هم هستيم
No it's not!
نه
What's with that solid gold dancer with his ass in the air?
اون رقاص طلايي هدفش چيه که تو هوا پرسه مي زنه؟
The dazzle dancer?
رقاص خيره کننده؟
Yeah, why don't you guys get married!
آره چرا شماها ازدواج نمي کنيد
I don't even know if he's gay.
من نمي دونم حتي که اون همجنس بازه يا نه
He's got like frosted hair.
انگار موهاش يخيه
George Michael has frosted hair and he's like totally straight.
جورج مايکل موهاي يخي داره و اون هم کاملا راسته
Adam, you're 21, you're like almost 30.
آدام تو 20 سالته انگار 30 ساله اي
You need to more aggressive.
بيشتر به خودت برس
What do I say?
من چي مي گم؟
Just be yourself.
خودت باش
What's that?
اون چيه؟
Tell him you liked his dancing.
بهش بگو که رقصش رو دوست داشتي
Oh my God, yeah, that F.I.T. Fag in training was there...
اوه خداي من آره اون اف اي تي
and of course Keith was there.
کيت هم اونجا بود
Let Carrie tell the story, she tells it so much better than you.
بذار کري تعريف کنه اون خيلي از تو قشنگتر تعريف مي کنه
I'm standing there talking to Keith Herring and this guy...
من اينجا وايستادم دارم با کيت هرينگ و اين يارو صحبت مي کنم
starts comparing him to Warhol.
ستاره هايي که اونو با وارل مقايسه مي کنن
It was so embarrassing.
شرم آور بود
He hates those comparisons, you know.
اون از اين جور مقايسه ها متنفره
God, it's so tragic.
خدايا چقدر حزن انگيزه
Well I guess Bela Lugosi ain't dead after all.
خب من حدس مي زنم بلا لوگوسي نمرده
He is dead, people like you killed him.
اون مرده مردمي مثل تو کشتنش
Oh, chill out.
اوه ، آروم باش
- Oh. - How did it go?
اوه چطور بود؟
Oh God, I'm such a loser.
اوه خداي من . خراب کردم باختم
You are not, would I be friends with a loser?
اينطور نيست ، يعني مي خواي بگي من با بازنده ها رفاقت مي کنم؟
Hey!
هي
Sorry about my friend Carrie.
بابت دوستم کري معذرت مي خوام
I'm Maura Bid and this is Rex Havoc.
من موارا بيد هستم واين رکس هاوکه
Cool look, Rex.
خوشگلي  رکس
Yeah, my last boyfriend was a goth,
آره آخرين دوست پسرم گات بود
are all of you as wild and nasty as he was?
همه شما به اندازه اون وحشي و کثيف هستيد؟
So you don't like to dance?
پس نمي خواي برقصي؟
Not to this music.
نه با اين آهنگ
Yeah, well it is Danceateria.
خب اينجا جاي رقصه
Yeah, more like Danceaqueeria.
آره واقعا
What is that, is that like a rib?
اون چيه؟ مثل دنده مي مونه
Yeah, you want one?
آره مي خواي؟
Na, na, I don't have much of an appetite if you catch my drift.
نه نه خيلي اشتها ندارم
Hey, you all want a bump?
هي مي خواين به خودتون يه تکوني بديد؟
The bump?
تکون؟
We're goths, we don't dance, we're dead.
ما گات هستيم و نمي رقصيم .ما مرديم
No, no, a bump of coke.
نه نه يه تکون نوشابه اي
Drugs?
مواد؟
Look at me, look at me.
نگام کن
Whew! Whoa!
واي اوه
I am so sorry.
واقعا معذرت مي خوام
It's alright, at least it's not the same one as last time.
اشکالي نداره . حداقل مثل قبليه نيست
Hey, Rex.
هي رکس
Oh my God,
اوه خداي من
he totally looks like the guy from the Ah-Ha video!
اون کاملا شبيه يارو تو برنامه آه ها هستش
Well, he can 'Take On Me' anytime.
خب اون هر وقت بخواد مي تونه باهام باشه
Do you think he still has some cocaine?
فکر مي کنه هنوز کوکائين داره؟
Oh my God, you're like totally addicted after like one bump!
اوه خداي من تو کاملا بعد يه بار معتاد شدي
No, I'm not.
نه نيستم
It was fun, it wasn't like I thought it would be.
خوب بود. اونجوري نبود که فکرشو مي کردم
Well it gave me the total Hershey squirts.
خب يه حس کاملا خوب بهم داد
I hear they cut it with baby laxatives.
شنيدم با ملين هاي بچه گونه قطعش مي کنن
Well, you said you wanted to lose some weight.
خب تو گفتي که مي خواي وزن کم کني
Hi.
سلام
Hey, you okay?
هي تو خوبي؟
Yeah, just my wrist.
آره فقط مچم
Where do you live?
کجا زندگي مي کني؟
Brooklyn.
بروکلين
Me too, me too.
منم همون جام
Sun's coming up, you want to watch it...
خورشيد داره طلوع مي کنه مي خواي تماشا کني
from the Brooklyn Bridge?
از روي پل بروکلين؟
Well I can't just leave my friend Rhonda.
خب نمي تونم دوستم روهاندا رو فراموش کنم
Good night.
شب بخير
- Good luck. - Stop it!
موفق باشي بس کن
So?
خب؟
Okay.
باشه
Yeah, I go to A.M.D.A., you know that theatre school uptown.
من به اي ام دي اي مي رم . مي دوني کجاست که ؟ مدرسه تئاتر بالاي شهر
We're doing The Sound of Music,
ما موسيقي مي خونيم
I'm up for the part of the Captain.
من دارم مي خونم براي نوازندگي
Perhaps I had a wicked childhood.
شايد دوران بچگي سختي رو داشتم
Wow.
واي
Perhaps I had a miserable youth...
شايد يه جووني غمگيني رو داشتم
Someday I'm going to dance on Broadway.
يه روزي توي برادوي مي رقصم
Watch this...
اينو ببين
Ew!
اي
Well, don't give up you've obviously got a huge talent.
خب نا اميد نشو واقعا يه توانايي عجيبي داري
Whew!
واي
Oh my God, just kidding.
اوه خداي من داشتم شوخي مي کردم
Give it here.
پسش بده
Hey, you know somehow I feel like...
هي مي دوني يه جورايي حس مي کنم
I've known you my whole life.
انگار تمام زندگي ام تو رو مي شناختم
Really, it's not just the drugs?
واقعا فقط براي مواد نيست؟
Oh no, this is way bigger than drugs.
نه خيلي بيشتر از مواد ارزش داره
Oh my God, I know.
اوه خداي من مي دونم
When I saw you dancing up there,
وقتي ديدمت که اون بالا داشتي مي رقصيدي
I knew you were the one.
مي دونستم که تو هموني هستي
I knew I was the one too.
منم مي دونستم که من خودشم
Where have you been my whole life?
تموم زندگي من تو کجا بودي؟
I've been looking for you.
داشتم دنبالت مي گشتم
Here I am.
حالا من اينجام
This is so fun.
چقدر عاليه
I love you.
دوستت دارم
I love you too.
منم دوستت دارم
What's your name again?
اسمت چي بود؟
Watch this.
اينو ببين
Wow!
واي
Oh good, more cocaine.
اوه خوبه ، بازم کوکائين
You have such an awesome body, do you like exercise and stuff?
چه بدن ورزيده اي داري ورزش و اينا رو دوست داري؟
Yeah, I think I'm the only gay guy...
آره من فکر مي کنم تنها يارويي هستم که
in the whole world that works out.
توي کل دنيا بيرون کار مي کنه
Hey, what's that muscle called on your arm?
هي اون عضله ي روي دستت چيه؟
Huh?
هان؟
Here?
اينجا؟
Tricep.
تريسپ
What about those, those ones.
اونا چي؟
Pecs.
پکس
Yeah, like that?
آره مثل اين؟
Lats...
لتس
Abs, quads, gluts...
آبس، کوادز، گالت
Oh my God I'm like the luckiest guy in the
اوه خداي من من خوشبخترين آدم
whole world right now.
روي زمينم
You are so f'ing hot.
تو واقعا تو دل برويي
Bicep.
بيسپ
Whoa...
واي
Puppy don't look.
نگاه نکن
You are an obsession. I cannot sleep.
# You are an obsession. I cannot sleep. #
I am your possession. Unopened at your feet.
# I am your possession. Unopened at your feet. #
There's no balance, no equality.
# There's no balance, no equality. #
#Be still, I will not accept defeat.
#Be still, I will not accept defeat. #
Sorry, sorry.
معذرت مي خوام
Yes I will have you.
# Yes I will have you. #
I will find a way and I will have...
# I will find a way and I will have... #
Hey.
هي
I thought you left.
فکر کردم رفتي
Oh, no I just came up for some fresh air.
نه اومدم اين بالا هواي آزاد بخورم
But if you can't beat them join them right?
اگه نمي توني باهاشون مبارزه کني بهشون بپيوند آره؟
Can I have a hit of that?
مي تونم ازش داشته باشم
Isn't this retro music awesome?
اين موسيقي به نظرت عالي نيست؟
It reminds me of slumber parties in grade school.
منو ياد جشنهاي دوران مدرسه مي اندازه
Wow!
واي
Somebody needs a drink!
يکي به يه نوشيدني نياز داره
No, no, I'm straight, sober.
نه نه من خوبم
Really?
واقعا؟
Wow.
واي
I would hate to be sober, that sucks ass.
من از مست نبودن متنفرم . مزخرفه
I don't see why sober people still get to smoke.
نمي دونم چرا آدمهاي عادي هنوز مي تونن سيگار بکشن
Nicotine is such a drug.
نيکوتين همچين مواده مخدريه
Yeah, but nicotine doesn't make me wander through gay bars...
آره ولي نيکوتين باعث نمي شه که برم به کلوپ هم جنس بازها
pinching my nipples and moaning, "pick me, pick me" to hot guys.
داد مي زنم و مي گم منو انتخاب کنيد منو انتخاب کنيد
Wow.
واي
Sounds like you did a lot of coke or crystal or crack.
انگار خيلي شيشه يا کراک زدي
And now you're an AA.
و حالا در هپروتي
But you don't go to crack meetings because they're too...
ولي خب به جشنهاي کراک نمي ري چون
hard core and you're just a nice Jewish boy at heart who can only...
اونا خيلي سنگدل هستند و تو فقط يه پسر يهودي مهربون هستي که فقط مي تونه
let lose when he's fucked up.
وقتي بهم ريخته است بد باشه
You have a lot of guilt which is why you need chemicals...
خيلي احساس گناه مي کني براي همينه بايد تحت نظر باشي
to squelch your conscious.
تا هوشياريت رو بدست بياري
You realize you just said all that out loud, right?
متوجه شدي که همه اون حرفا رو. الان بلند داد زدي. درسته؟
Oh, I'm studying acting so I pick up on...
خب من بازيگري مي خونم براي همينه که
people's personalities, you know?
درباره شخصيت افراد تحقيق مي کنم
Guys think they're so mysterious,
مردها فکر مي کنن که خيلي مرموزن
but most are just really transparent.
ولي خيلي هاشون واقعا تابلوئند
Well I appreciate the completely superficial deconstruction...
خب من تحسين مي کنم بازسازي کاملا ماهرانه اي رو که
of my character but I think I'm a little more...
از شخصيتم داشتي من فکر مي کنم از اوني که تو فکر مي کني
complex than you think.
يه مقداري پيچيده ترم
Hi everybody.
سلام به همگي
My name is Mary and I used to be a bipolar crack addict.
اسم من ماري و من قبلا معتاد به کراک بودم
But now I'm just bipolar.
ولي الان نيستم
Yeah!
آره
Welcome, welcome, welcome to the midnight...
خوش آمديدي. خوش آمديد به جلسه شبانه
whip that crack fellowship.
دوستان کراکي
This is a crack meeting, tonight's topic is crack.
اين يه جلسه در مورد کراک . موضوع امشب کراکه
Okay.
باشه
Ah...
آ...
Happy birthday.
تولدت مبارک
Yeah, hello!
بله سلام
Hey honey, just calling to wish you know who a happy Bert-day.
سلام عزيزم من فقط تماس گرفتم که بهت بگم تولدت مبارک
Well I'd put him on the phone but he's in a cake hole.
خب مي تونم بيارمش پاي تلفن ولي الان داره مي کشه
I should be reported to the Humane Society.
بايد به جامعه بشريت معرفي بشم
Oh please, I've eaten more than that in one sitting.
اوه خواهش مي کنم من بيشتر از حد خوردم
Remember my sister's wedding, she's still mad
عروسي خواهرم رو يادت هست هنوز عصبانيه ازم
she didn't get a piece.
اون يه تيکه هم گيرش نيومد
Right.
درسته
And besides one of the many advantages of being a dog...
و در کنار همه مزاياي سگ بودن
is that get to eat like a pig.
اينه که مي توني مثل يه خوک بخوري
Hey, fatso, ready to go on?
هي فاتسو آماده اي که بري؟
Speaking of pigs, Lou just propositioned me again.
از خوک ها گفتي لو منو دوباره تحريک کردي
Hey, hey everybody having a good time?
هي هي همگي داره بهتون خوش مي گذره؟
Let me hear you say 'yeah'!
بذاريد بشنوم که همه مي گيد آره
All right.
باشه
Oh, I'm hanging by a thread here the audiences have been really...
من اينجا دارم تهديد مي شم همه حضار واقعا
tough and I'm sweating like Whitney Houston...
سخت گيري کردن و دارم مثل ويتني هوستون عرق مي ريزم
going though customs.
با اين رسم هاي سخت
Uh...
آه
Maybe you might want to, you know,
شايد بخواي که
come up with some new material,
با يکي که بيشتر سبک داره کار کني
you know, since you lost the weight.
مي دوني از وقتي وزن کم کردي
What are you talking about?
داري از چي حرف مي زني؟
Help me Rhonda, yeah, get her out of my pants.
کمکم کن روندا آره اونو ازم دور کن
Thank you.
ممنونم
Oh shit, he's singing a song.
اوه لعنتي اون داره يه شعر مي خونه
Ladies and gentlemen Rhonda Gernon...
خانم ها و آقايون روندا گرون
Whew!
واي
I know what you're thinking.
مي دونم داري به چي فکر مي کني
Doesn't she have a pretty face?
واقعا صورتش زيبا نيست؟
And what a personality!
و چه شخصيتي داره
If only I didn't get my dresses made by Omar the tent maker.
اگه که لباسامو عمر برام ندوخته بود
I'm so fat, I eat with a forklift.
اونقدر چاقم که با چنگال غذا مي خورم
I'm so fat, when I back up, my ass beeps.
اونقدر چاقم که از پشت افتضاحم
Fashioned from actual ceramic chips...
با سراميک ساخته شده و
recovered at Ground Zero.
به حالت اوليه در اومده
This commemorative plate will make a fitting addition to...
اين بشقاب هم مي تونه به جمع 9/11 تا
your other 9/11 collectibles.
کلکسيونتون اضافه بشه
Featuring an American bald eagle, look at her there
اگه مي خواي يه عقاب کچل آمريکايي رو ببيني مي توني بهش نگاه کني
- In all her majestic glory - Oh my God.
با همه زيبايي هاي خيره کننده اي که داره اوه خداي من
With a gorgeous single cubic zirconia tear...
با يه قطره اشک شيشه اي زيبا که
running down her furrowed face.
از گونه هاش داره مي آد پايين
Look at that, now...
ببينش
Oh!
اوه
Geez!
خداي من
Somebody...
يک نفر
Help!
کمک کنه
Help me!
کمکم کنيد
Oh my God, somebody help me!
اوه خداي من يکي کمکم کنه
Sir, animals are not allowed here,
جناب ورود حيوانات اينجا ممنوعه
hospital policy.
سياست بيمارستانه
What do you mean 'hospital policy'?!
منظورت چيه سياست بيمارستانه؟
You are going to have to keep your voice down sir.
بايد صداتون رو بياريد پايين جناب
Now there is a very good animal hospital over on First Avenue.
بعد از کوچه اول يه بيمارستان خوب براي حيوانات هست
I'm not on First Avenue, I'm on Tenth Avenue and there are...
من کوچه اول نيستم و الان در کوچه دهم هستم
doctors here, medical equipment, and he has a heart and brain...
و اينجا هم دکترا هستن با تجهيزات پزشکي و اون هم يه قلب و مغز داره
and lungs just like a normal person.
و ريه درست مثل يه آدم طبيعي
Sir, please come with me.
جناب لطفا با من بيايد
There was an accident, I stabbed him.
تصادف شد و من زدم بهش
I stabbed him accidentally.
من تصادفا زدم بهش
Hello.
سلام
We have another dog stabber down here.
ما يه سگ تصادفيه ديگه هم اينجا داريم
Sir the hospitals doesn't admit animals, we have told you.
جناب بيمارستان حيوانات رو نمي پذيره ما بهتون گفته بوديم
This is not an animal, this is my child.
اين حيوون نيست اين بچه منه
I'm a single gay man in New York, don't you understand?!
من يه مرد مجرد هم جنس بازم که توي نيويورک زندگي مي کنه. مي فهمي؟
Rob, Rob, it's okay. It's okay.
راب راب مشکلي نيست
Sir, bring the dog on back, okay.
جناب سگ رو برگردون اينجا باشه
Thank you.
ممنون
At least there is still one caring person...
حداقل هنوز يه نفر هست که بفهمه و اهميت بده
left in the medical establishment.
که توي مراکز پزشکي باشه
Sir.
جناب
What is this National Freak Day?
اين چيه روز ملي ترسوندن؟
We've got a lady yelling at her vagina out there.
ما يه زن اون بيرون داريم که داره سر خودش داد مي زنه
Ah, the pictures are back.
آه  عکسها رسيدن
The dog has a bruised rib which was...
سگه عضله اش پاره شده
I'm sorry I can't hear you.
معذرت مي خوام صداتو نم شنوم
Oh, sorry.
اوه معذرت مي خوام
X-rays, yeah your dog has a bruised rib which the knife...
عکس ها بله سگ شما يه پارگي روي عضلات داشته که چاقو
must have grazed while it entered.
حتما وقتي که وارد شده پاره اش کرده
See there's a little clouding in the abdomen region which...
ببينيد يه پارگي جزئي در اين محدوده هست که
we'd expect in a puncture wound.
ما انتظار يه زخم رو اينجا داريم
Is he bleeding internally?
خونريزي داخلي داره؟
Yeah, a little, but you know nothing life threatening.
بله يه مقداري ولي چيز نگران کنننده اي نيست
Oh thank you, thank you so much.
اوه ممنونم خيلي خيلي ممنونم
I can't thank you enough for helping us.
من ديگه نمي دونم با چه زبوني تشکر کنم
Quite all right.
باشه
You want to go see him now?
مي خواي بري ببينيش
- Yeah. - Right this way.
بله از اين طرف
Hi, oh...
سلام اوه
You know I have to say that his fat protected him...
مي دوني بايد بگم که چاقي اش کمکش کرد
from the knife, although in the long run...
از ضربه چاقو اگرچه در دراز مدت بهتره
you might want to put him on a diet.
شايد بخوايد که بهش رژيم بديد
Oh, yeah, I don't know why he's so fat.
اوه آره نمي دونم چرا اينقدر چاقه
- I'm Adam, by the way. - Oh, I'm Doctor Hicks, Steven.
من آدام هستم من دکتر هيکس هستم ايتسون
Are you a veterinarian?
دکتر متخصص حيوانات هستيد؟
Actually I'm a shrink, I do outpatient...
درواقع من عمومي هستم
mental health services here.
اينجا خدمات سلامتي رواني داريم
I went to medical school, I was going to be a veterinarian,
من رفتم به دانشگاه پزشکي مي خواستم دکتر حيوانات بشم
I actually love animals.
من عاشق حيواناتم
Why didn't you?
چرا نرفتي؟
I couldn't stand the idea of dealing with neurotic...
نمي تونستم فکر مقابله با صاحبان حيوانات رو بکنم
Oh, sorry.
اوه معذرت مي خوام
It's okay.
اشکالي نداره
It is sad how people attribute human qualities to animals...
تاسف آوره که انسانها چطور کارايي انساني رو به حيوانات مي دن
instead of just eating their flesh or wearing their fur.
به جاي اينکه گوشتوشن رو بخورن و از پشمشون لباس بپوشن
So Adam, let's talk about you now.
خب آدام از خودت بگو
Me?
من؟
You want to tell me what drove you to stab your dog?
مي خواي برام بگي چي شد که سگت اينطور شد؟
Oh, it was an accident.
اوه يه تصادف بود
Look I love this dog more than I love myself.
ببين من اين سگو بيشتر از خودم دوست دارم
I know it sounds dumb, but I'm not crazy.
مي دونم احمقانه بنظر مي رسه ولي من ديوونه نيستم
I know you're not crazy.
مي دونم که ديوونه نيستي
You know actually it's refreshing to meet somebody who
مي دوني بارم جالبه ملاقات با کسي که
loves someone or something that much.
به کسي يا چيزي اينقدر علاقه داره
Oh.
اوه
Hey, greetings gay doctor roommate!
هي خوش آمديد هم اتاقيه دکتر
Tough day at the 'orifice'?
روز سختي بود؟
A woman who thinks God speaks through her vagina.
يه زني که فکر مي کنه خدا بهش الهام مي کنه
Oh, wait, Polly?
اوه صبر کن. پلي؟
Oh no...
اوه نه
no please.
نه خواهش مي کنم
Blond, thirties, five-eight.
بور سي ساله پنج تا هشت
You had sex with a homeless woman?
تو با يه خانم بي خانمان ارتباط داشتي؟
It was kind of sweet actually,
يه جورايي شيرين بود
it's not the way you make it sound.
اونطوري که تو فکر مي کني نيست
For God's sake.
محض رضاي خدا
We actually cuddled a lot, it was very intimate.
خيلي خودموني بود
Yeah, well she was probably cold.
آره خوب اون حتما خيلي يخ بوده
You know homeless people have needs.
مي دوني که بي خانمان ها يه نيازهايي دارن
You know they need love like other folks.
مي دوني اونا هم مثل بقيه احتياج به محبت دارن
I helped her, I provided a service for her actually,
من بهش کمک کردم و براش يه سرويس آماده کردم
you know for five minutes her vagina stopped talking to her.
مي دوني براي 5 دقيقه ديگه باهاش حرف نزد
Michael I'm going to take a shower for both of us.
مايکل من مي خوام برم دوش رو براي جفتمون آماده کنم
Well, your mother would be happy, marrying a doctor.
خب مادرت خوشحال مي شه از اينکه با يه دکتر ازدواج مي کني
- Is he Jewish? - I don't think so.
يهوديه؟ فکر نمي کنم
Whatever, I'll never see him again unless I go insane.
به هر حال ديگه نمي بينمش مگه اينکه ديوونه بشم
Adam, we're like in our thirties, we're almost 40,
آدام ما سي سالمونه نزديکه 40
you need to be more aggressive.
بايد بيشتر تلاش کني
Why don't you go back to the hospital?
چرا بر نمي گردي به بيمارستان؟
- No! - Why not?
نه چرا نه؟
He already thinks I'm a crazy pet person.
اون همين الانشم فکر مي کنه که من يه آدم ديوونه ي حيوونا هستم
You're the only person I know that showers before the gym.
تو تنها کسي هستي که مي شناسم که قبل از ورزش کردن دوش مي گيره
Well, I need to blow off some steam.
خب بايد يه خورده بخار بگيرم
- Among other things. - Uh-huh, that's right.
از بين چيزاي ديگه آهان درسته
God, you gay guys are so lucky.
خداي من شماها چقدر خوش شناسين
You get to connect and make love...
مي تونيد ارتباط برقرار کنيد و عاشق بشيد
to someone different every night.
با يه نفر متفاوت هر شب
Yeah.
آره
If women were as promiscuous as you there'd be like
اگه زنها هم مثل شما بيقيد بودن
orgies in the street.
مي شدن مثل عياش هاي خيابوني
Thanks to you there already are.
به لطف شما الانشم هستن
Oh no, I brought her back here.
اوه نه برش گردوندم
Well, have fun having gay, anonymous sex...
خب خوش بگذره بهتون
in the low self esteem room.
توي اتاق پايين
Thanks.
ممنون
Hey, you're hot, I wish I had your body,
هي کاش هيکل تو رو داشتم
but like with my face.
ولي خب با صورت خودم
I wish you did too.
منم آرزو دارم که داشتي
God, don't you just love this gym it feels so good to sweat
خداي من، تو از اين باشگاه خوشت نمي آد
out the tina, you know what I mean?
جاي خوبيه براي عرق کردن. منظورم رو مي فهمي؟
Actually I don't, I don't use drugs and neither should you.
در واقع نمي فهمم. من مواد مصرف نمي کنم و تو هم نبايد مصرف کني
Ew!
اي
It sounds like somebody had a bad experience with drugs.
انگار يکي تجربه تلخي با مواد داشته
Excuse me?
ببخشيد؟
No, it's okay, I'm just really observant.
نه اشکالي نداره.
I notice things that other guys might not.
من چيزايي رو متوجه مي شم که شايد مردهاي ديگه نفهمن
Is that so?
واقعا؟
Yeah.
آره
I'm going to be an actor so I pick up...
من مي خوام يه بازيگر بشم براي همين
on people's personalities.
روي شخصيت مردم بررسي مي کنم
You don't do drugs because you have...
تو مواد مصرف نمي کني چون
what they call... 'control issues'.
چيزي که اونا بهش مي گن مواد کنترل رو داري
You're like totally afraid to be out of control of your body...
تو کاملا نگراني که چيزي رو که کنترل بدنت رو ازت بگيره رو از دست بدي
or let someone see you in a less than perfect light.
يا اينکه بذاري کسي تو رو توي نور کم ببينه
You're really afraid of letting your hair down,
واقعا مي ترسي که موهاتو بريزي پايين
unless it has to do with sex,
مگر اينکه ارتباطي در کار باشه
and then you can completely cut lose and...
بعدش مي توني کاملا بري و
Hey!
هي
Sorry, sorry.
ببخشيد ببخشيد
Ew!
اي
Dogs are so gross!
سگها چندشن
How can someone love something that shits...
چطوري مي توني چيزي رو که گند مي زنه رو دوست داشت
right in front of them?
دقيقا جلوشون؟
Excuse me,
ببخشيد
could you eat any of these birds if you had to?
تو اگه مجبور بشي اين پرنده ها رو مي خوري؟
You know, like if terrorists poisoned the food supply.
مي دوني مثل وقتي که تروريست ها جيره غذايي رو مسموم کنن
Oh look everyone, we have a duck in flight directly above us.
اوه همه نگاه کنن يه اردک داريم که بالاي سرمون داره پرواز مي کنه
Oh my God! Quick, somebody call 911!
اوه خداي من سريع يکي اورژانس رو خبر کنه
Long live the NRA!
زنده باد ان آر اي
I am so sorry, this usually doesn't happen.
من واقعا معذرت مي خوام . معمولا اين اتفاقات نمي افته
Hey, you okay?
هي تو خوبي؟
Yeah, I'm fine, I just bruised a rib.
آره خوبم همين الان يه عضله رو بريدم
Oh my God, it is you. It's you the dog guy.
اوه خداي من تويي . ياروي سگي
- Hi. - Hey.
سلام
Wow. What a coincidence.
واي چه تصادفي
How is your dog, speaking of bruised ribs?
حال سگت چطوره؟
He's all better.
بهتره
He pees on the floor sometimes, or is that me?
گاهي اوقات روي زمين خرابکاري مي کنه. يا شايدم کار من باشه؟
So what do you do,
خب چيکار مي کني
like bird watching tours around here?
تور تماشاي پرندگان راه انداختي اينجا؟
Yeah, you thought you were the only one to deal with crazies.
آره فکر مي کني تو تنها کسي هستي که با ديونه ها سر و کار داري؟
That was actually pretty heroic of you,
واقعا کارت عالي بود
you know, tackling that guy, getting all dirty.
مي دوني مقابله با اون يارو و کثيف شدي
Oh well, it was heroic of you to save my dog...
کارت قهرمانانه بود که جون سگم رو نجات دادي
and I don't mind you getting dirty.
و مهم نيست که کثيف شدي
Oh, I know.
مي دونم
You know, I'm really sorry, I was such a mess at the hospital.
معذرت مي خوام من توي بيمارستان خرابکاري کردم
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
صبر کن يه لحظه
Here, let me do something.
بيا بذار يه کاري کنم
Wait a minute, come here.
صبر کن بيا اينجا
It's all right, just... here.
هيچي نيست. اينجا
Here, look at me.
اينجا بهم نگاه کن
There, that's better.
آهان حالا بهتر شد
So listen, I'm going to be an aggressive type person here...
گوش بده من قراره يه آدم ديگه اي باشم اينجا
and, uh, take you out to dinner some time.
و تو رو يه وقتي به شام بيرون ببرم
Oh, you don't have to do that.
اوه بايد اينکارو کني
- No, I want to. - Really, it's fine.
نه ولي مي خوام واقعا. مشکلي نداره
- Really, it's okay.
نه من مي خوام واقعا باشه
- Really, I want to. - Really, it's fine.
واقعا مي خوام واقعا مشکلي نداره
- But I want to. - It's all right.
ولي مي خوام مشکلي نداره
I'd kind of like to.
من يه جورايي دوست دارم
Oh, I don't know, it's fine.
اوه نمي دونم مشکلي نيست
But I'd like to.
ولي من دوست دارم
Really you should...
واقعا بايد
I know... let me ask you out to dinner.
مي دونم بذار ازت دعوت کنم شام بياي باهام بيرون
No, that's okay.
نه خوبه
No, I'm serious I want to.
نه من جدي ام مي خوام
No, you don't have to.
نه تو نبايد
But I want to.
ولي مي خوام
I'm flattered but...
من هيجان زده شدم ولي
No, really come on I want to.
نه بيا ديگه من مي خوام
Listen, I should take you out to dinner to thank you...
ببين من بايد تو رو به شام دعوت کنم که ازت تشکر کنم
for what you did for Burt.
براي کاري که براي برت کردي
Oh...
اوه
if it's just about your dog, I mean,
اگه فقط به خاطر سگت هست منظورم اينه که
you know, it's really not necessary.
مي دوني خيلي ضروري نيست
If you're asking me on a date, like a romantic type thing,
اگه داري باهام قرار مي ذاري مي دوني يه جورايي از نوع رمانتيک
you know then I would maybe have to say yes to such...
شايد اون موقع بگم آره
an aggressive type person.
به چنين آدمي
Well it just so happens to be a romantic date type thing,
خب انگار که يه قراره رمانتيکه
so yeah, that's right.
خب آره اين درسته
- Okay.
باشه
Okay, yeah good.
باشه خوبه
Um.
اهم
Wow.
واي
How about tomorrow night?
فردا شب چطوره؟
Tomorrow night's great, where?
فردا شب عاليه. کجا؟
Uh...
اه
how about right here in the park, you know the bath house.
همين جا توي پارک چطوره خونه قايق
The Boat House?
خونه قايق؟
Um, I know, Sona. Sona on 6th at 6.
من سونا رو مي شناسم. سونا توي خيابون 6
Yeah, okay, great.
آره خوب عاليه
- Good. - All right.
خوبه باشه
Okay, well I'll see you there.
باشه خوب مي بينمت
- All right. - Bye.
خداحافظ
Are you sure you want to do this?
مطمئني که مي خواي اينکارو کني؟
Will you chill out, you sound like a jealous wife.
آروم مي شي . مثل يه زن حسود صحبت مي کني
Well you know you're going to have to change your whole
خب بايد کل رويه ي زندگي ات رو
lifestyle, you know.
عوض کني
He's got a dog, you're going to have to hide all the knives.
اون يه سگ داره و تو بايد همه چاقوها رو قايم کني
Michael, it's just a date, okay.
مايکل فقط يه قراره باشه
Look, I'm 36 years old, maybe I'm tired of one hot...
ببين من 36 سالمه شايد خسته شدم از
sexual encounter after another.
يه ارتباط پشت سر هم
Maybe I want to find out what it's like to have okay sex...
شايد بخوام بفهمم که چطور مي شه يه ارتباط درست داشت
with the same person on a regular basis.
با يه فرد مشابه در يک مورد معمولي
I'm very disappointed in you, Steve.
من واقعا ازت ناراحتم استيو
Obviously you're not the person that I thought you were.
معلومه تو اون آدمي نيستي که من فکرشو مي کردم
Michael, I can still see you.
مايکل هنوز مي بينمت
Okay, one apple martini, diet coke.
باشه يه مارتيني سيب و نوشابه رژيمي
You, uh, you don't drink?
تو مشروب نمي نوشي؟
No, I'm on antibiotics.
نه
Anything... communicable?
هر چي؟
Oh, no, no, nothing communicable.
اوه نه نه هيچي
No, it's been awhile since I've communicated with anyone.
مدتي از وقتي با کسي ارتباطي داشتم گذشته
You mean since uh, since you've had sex?
منظورت از وقتيکه که ارتباط داشتي؟
How long?
چقدر؟
Oh, you know, I don't know...
مي دوني نمي دونم
not that long, like six months.
نه اونقدر طولاني مثلا 6 ماه
Wow.
واي
Although I did meet this one guy on the phone sex line who came over,
اگرچه با اين يارو از پشت تلفن آشنا شدم
but he lied about what he looked like, you know.
ولي اون در مورد شکلش دروغ گفت
When he showed up he was like 20 years older...
وقتي ديدمش 20 سال پيرتر بود
and 50 pounds heavier than he said... and short.
و 50 کيلو چاق تر از چيزي که گفته بود و کوتاه بود
Well he was a dwarf, or a midget, I get them confused.
اون يه کوتوله بوده
Yeah.
آره
He had crossed eyes and burns on his face.
چشاش چپ بود و جاي سوختگي روي صورتش
No ears.
گوش نداشت
I think he might have been born with a hair lip,
فکر کنم مادرزادي اينطوري بود
but that could have been from the fire, you know.
مي فهمي
Yeah.
آره
I don't think he should have lied about those things, you know?
فکر نمي کنم لازم بود در اين موارد دروغ بگه
No.
نه
I told him that too right after we had sex.
من بعد از اينکه با هم رابطه داشتيم بهش گفتم
Thank you.
ممنون
You know I have to tell you I don't go on dates very often.
بايد بهت بگم که خيلي زود به زود سر قرار نمي رم
But you know ever since I saw you at the E.R.,
ولي مي دوني از وقتي تو رو توي اي آر ديدم
you seem familiar some how?
يه جورايي آشنا بنظر مي رسي
Hmm.
همم
Did you grow up on Long Island?
توي جزيره ي لانگ بزرگ شدي؟
Uh-uh.
ام
- Texas. - You don't have an accent.
تگزاس لهجه نداري
Where did you go to college?
کجا رفتي دانشگاه؟
I went to NYU briefly but it didn't work out.
رفتم به نيويورک ولي ادامه ندادم
I don't know, I guess it's just one of those things, huh?
نمي دونم فکر مي کنم يکي از اون حالت هاست؟
Oh, well I was in a porn movie once, maybe you saw it.
خب من توي يه فيلم بودم يه بار شايد ديده باشي
Really?
واقعا؟
No.
نه
Okay.
باشه
Really?
واقعا؟
No.
نه
No, no.
نه نه
So you're an ornithologist?
پس تو دکتر پرنده هايي؟
No, I just watch birds for a living.
نه فقط به پرندهها نگاه مي کنم
Yeah, business can be slow in the winter,
آره کار و کاسبي توي زمستون مي خوابه
but it's a steady paycheck and I'm trying to keep it simple...
ولي حقوق ثابتي داره و من دارم سعي مي کنم ساده نگهش دارم
right now.
در حال حاضر
Keep it simple?
ساده؟
Yeah.
آره
Listen, I don't have an infection.
ببين من بيماري مسري ندارم
I'm in recovery and part of that is being honest about that.
دارم دوران نقاهت رو مي گذرونم و در اين مورد هم صادقم
Good for you, Adam. Good for you.
خوبه آدام
Listen I deal with a lot of people...
ببين من با خيلي ها سرو کار دارم
who have addictive personalities.
که شخصيت هاي معتاد دارن
Hey, wake up, it's not over till the fat lady sings...
هي بلند شو تا وقتي اون خانم چاقه نخونه تموم نمي شه
and I ain't sung yet.
و من هنوز نخوندم
Boy, tough crowd.
پسر چه جمعيتي
Remember ladies and gentlemen, if you throw any...
يادتون باشه خانم ها و اقايون اگه
wilted vegetables I will simply eat them.
سبزيجات گنديده پرتاب کنيد به سادگي مي خورمشون
Although pork ribs are my favorite,
اگرچه اينا مورد علاقه من هستن
feel free to throw those.
براي پرت کردنشون احساس راحتي کنيد
Isn't it funny how the more ribs you eat...
جالب نيست  هر چي بيشتر ماهيچه مي خوري
the less you can see of your own?
کمتر مي توني ماله خودت رو ببيني
You know, I know her, I think.
من اونو مي شناسم. فکر مي کنم
Are those chocolate covered crickets I hear in the audience?
اون صدايي که مي شنوم از توي حضار جيرجيرک ها کاکائويي هستن؟
- Yeah. - She was funny.
آره جالب بود
Well you're sweet to say that but really she wasn't.
خب ممنونم که گفتي ولي واقعا نبود
Ah, thanks for coming.
ممنون که اومدي
Yeah.
آره
Ah, what a shitty audience, right?
اه چه گندي. حضار درسته؟
This is Steve.
اين استيوه
Oh, the doctor with the heart of gold, nice to meet you.
اوه دکتر با قلب طلايي . ازديدنتون خوشحالم
I know you, right, don't I?
من تو رو مي شناسم درسته؟
Well, I was just on stage.
خب من همين الان روي صحنه بودم
Wait a minute.
يه لحظه صبر کن
Oh my God.
اوه خداي من
Marie's... Marie's Crisis.
مري
- You're the cocktail waitress... - Oh yeah, yeah, yeah.
تو خدمتکار کوکتل هستي او آره آره
I work there on weekends, this place doesn't really pay,
من آخر هفته ها اونجا کار مي کنم اينجا حقوق خوبي نمي دن
so...
خب
Right, I guess you don't recognize me.
درسته فکر کنم منو نمي شناسي
I'm too self absorbed to notice other people.
من خيلي درونگرا هستم و متوجه ديگران نمي شم
I'm sorry did you say something?
معذرت مي خوام شما چيزي گفتي؟
Okay.
باشه
Excuse me I'm going to take care of some business.
ببخشيد مي خوام به کارام برسم
He's so cute.
خيلي بانمکه
I know, I know he's so cute and we've been...
مي دونم که خيلي بانمکه و ما
having like the best time.
بهترين زمان رو با هم داشتيم
Like the more I talk to him the more it's like I've known him...
انگار هر چي بيشتر باهاش حرف مي زنم انگار بيشتر مي شناسمش
my whole life.
همه زندگي ام انگار شناختمش
Past lives.
زندگي گذشته
Yeah.
آره
You're about as funny as a heart attack.
تو به اندازه ي يه سکته قلبي خنده داري
Oh, thanks dad!
اوه ممنونم پدر
Okay, well here I am.
باشه خب من اينجام
Oh.
اوه
What!
چي
Well aren't you worried about getting gay bashed or yelled at?
خب نگران نيستي که سرت داد و فرياد کنن يا طردت کنن؟
No!
نه
No, my God nothing like that's ever happened to me.
نه خداي من هيچ چيزي اينطوري تا به حال به سرم نيومده
Yeah, it's just like every time I expressed affection in public...
آره مثل هر دفعه ايت که توي عموم احساسات بروز مي دادم
some asshole from Jersey throws a beer bottle at me.
يه آشغال از جرسي يه بطري مشروب به سمتم پرتاب کرده
Wow.
واي
Sounds like you've had really bad luck.
انگار که بد شانسي آوردي
Oh... Burt, Burt, Burt, look at you.
اوه برت برت برت نگاش کن
Give me five! Hey!
بزن قدش هي
Look at you, you're all better now.
نگاش کن الان خيلي بهتر شدي
Oh!
اوه
Did you come?
اومدي؟
No, I think your dog is licking my foot.
نه فکر کنم سگت داره پامو ليس مي زنه
Oh.
اوه
Burt, go to your bed, go!
برت برو به تختت بخواب
I'm sorry.
معذرت مي خوام
I don't think he understands what's happening to his daddy.
فکر کنم نمي فهمه پدرش چش شده
Do you understand what's happening to his daddy?
متوجه مي شي پدرش چي شده؟
No.
نه
- Yes, yeah. - Come here.
آره آره بيا اينجا
Bells will ring, and angels sing.
# Bells will ring, and angels sing. #
there's something in the air.
# there's something in the air. #
Cupid brings the start of spring,
# Cupid brings the start of spring, #
with something to declare.
# with something to declare. #
And now it's love, love, love...
# And now it's love, love, love... #
So delightfully, it's love, love, love, love, love.
# So delightfully, it's love, love, love, love, love. #
Romeo was smitten, Aphrodite bitten.
# Romeo was smitten, Aphrodite bitten. #
Juliet was reeling, now I know the feeling.
# Juliet was reeling, now I know the feeling. #
My heart's palpatatin', hyperventilatin',
# My heart's palpatatin', hyperventilatin', #
#from the kissing and the smackin', aphrodisiacking.
#from the kissing and the smackin', aphrodisiacking. #
I'm in love, love, love.
# I'm in love, love, love. #
What a gas to be in love, love, love, love, love.
# What a gas to be in love, love, love, love, love. #
Love, love, love, like it has to be,
# Love, love, love, like it has to be, #
in love, love, love, love, love.
# in love, love, love, love, love. #
Who'd of thought that you and me'd be talking L-O-V-E?
# Who'd of thought that you and me'd be talking L-O-V-E? #
You can guarantee that we both agree.
# You can guarantee that we both agree. #
I know it seems askew,
# I know it seems askew, #
and relatively new to me, you'll say I do
# and relatively new to me, you'll say I do #
because we're both in love, love, love.
# because we're both in love, love, love. #
What a gas to be in love, love, love, love, love.
# What a gas to be in love, love, love, love, love. #
Love, love, love, like it has to be
# Love, love, love, like it has to be #
in love, love, love, love, love.
# in love, love, love, love, love. #
Two ships in the night,
# Two ships in the night, #
became a cruise ship of delight,
# became a cruise ship of delight, #
on an ocean of anomoniquity.
# on an ocean of anomoniquity. #
The owl is on the prowl
# The owl is on the prowl #
and though the pussycat did scowl.
# and though the pussycat did scowl. #
She winked her eye and said come sail with me.
# She winked her eye and said come sail with me. #
And then it's love, love, love.
# And then it's love, love, love. #
So delightfully it's love, love, love, love, love.
# So delightfully it's love, love, love, love, love. #
Love, love, love it's so right for me
# Love, love, love it's so right for me #
in love, love, love, love, love.
# in love, love, love, love, love. #
Love, love, love.
# Love, love, love. #
Love, love, love...
# Love, love, love... #
You know I actually wanted to be a dancer at one point.
من يه وقتايي مي خواستم که رقاص باشم
Really?
واقعا؟
I was a theatre major, couldn't deal with Bohemia,
مدير يه تئاتر بودم نتونستم به بوهيما کنار بيام
such a messy lifestyle, very, very messy.
يه زندگي قاطي و بهم ريخته خيلي بهم ريخته
What are you doing?
داري چيکار مي کني؟
When was your last relationship?
آخرين ارتباطتت کي بوده؟
Um, by relationship what exactly do you mean?
منظورت از ارتباط دقيقا چيه؟
Your last boyfriend, lover, homosexual lifetime...
آخرين دوست پسرت عشق
commitment partner companion?
آخرين جفت و هم دمت؟
I've never really had a long term one.
من هيچ وقت يه ارتباط طولاني مدت نداشتم
No one's really held my interest for that long, you know?
هيچ کس تا به حال اين همه توجهم رو جلب نکرده
Great.
عاليه
No, wait a minute, wait a minute, now.
نه صبر کن يه دقيقه
You know when I was a kid I figured I'd grow up,
مي دوني وقتي که بچه بودم فهميدم که بزرگ مي شم و
meet a nice guy, have a big wedding.
با يه مرد خوب آشنا مي شم و يه عروسي بزرگ مي گيرم
It all had to be a certain way, you know.
همه اش بايد به يه روش مخصوص انجام مي شد
Like in the movies I'd seen.
مثل فيلم ها که ديد ه بودم
Yeah, me too.
آره منم همين طور
You know, I'd always watch those movies and I'd superimpose...
من هميشه اون فيلم ها رو تماشا مي کردم و
myself over the man and then the woman,
خودم رو کنار اون مرد تصور مي کردم
you know, I'd go back and forth.
مي رفتم عقب و
Like in one scene I'd be Julia Roberts and then in the next...
توي يه صحنه جوليا رابرتز بودم و در صحنه بعدي
scene I'd be, you know like Julia Roberts.
مي شدم شبيه جوليا رابرتز
Really?
واقعا؟
I'm Meg Ryan.
من مگ رايان هستم
Hi Meg.
سلام مگ
Yeah, you're blonde.
آره تو بلندي
Ah, Julia come on.
آه جوليا بيا
Hey, you ever gone gay two stepping over...
تا به حال به  مرکز دو پله اي همجنس بازها رفتي؟
at the Big Apple Rodeo in Midtown?
توي مرکز شهر؟
Two stepping, no I can barely one step.
دو پله اي. نه من به سختي مي تونم يک پله اي رو تحمل کنم
What do you wear to something like that?
چي تنت مي کني؟
Oh my God, it's ho-down.
اوه خداي من
All right come here, come here, come here.
خب بيا اينجا
I don't know how to do this.
من نمي دونم که چطوري بايد اينکارو کنم
Relax, okay, it's really easy.
آروم باش باشه خيلي آسونه
All you do, okay look at this, you go, quick quick step, step.
تنها کاري که مي کني اينه که به اين نگاه مي کني و پله پله ميري
Quick, quick step, step, exactly.
تند تند پله پله دقيقا
It's just a repetition of the same move except we're...
تکرار همون حرکت مي شه به جز وقتي که
going to be going that way, all right?
مي خواي اينطوري بري. باشه؟
- Okay. - Ready, here we go.
باشه آماده اي . بريم
And quick, quick step. Good.
و تند تند پله خوبه
Quick, quick, exactly.
تند تند دقيقا
Ow!
او
I'm sorry, oh, I'm sorry.
معذرت مي خوام معذرت مي خوام
It's okay, sorry, let's keep going all right?
اشکالي نداره. ادامه بديم
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
معذرت مي خوام. معذرت مي خوام
It's all right, look you'll get the hang of it, all right.
اشکالي نداره قلقلش مي آد دستت
Let's just keep going, here we go.
بيا ادامه بديم
Here we go, and quick, quick step.
بريم. تند تند پله
Good.
خوبه
Hey, Steve.
هي استيو
Hey, Andy.
هي اندي
This is uh... Adam.
اين آدامه
Looks like someone's having a little bit of trouble here.
انگار يکي اينجا به مشکل خورده
Yeah, well I'm Jewish, you know give me a bottle dance...
آره من يهودي ام يه رقص کنم و
and I'm fine.
خوب مي شم
Well, I teach private lessons, so if you ever want to take it...
خب من تدريس خصوصي مي کنم اگه خواستي بياي
seriously at all, you just let me know.
جدي مي گم فقط بهم خبر بده
Actually, Andy is a really great instructor.
درواقع اندي يه معلم خيلي خوبه
Not that you ever needed any instructing.
نه اينکه تو هيچ وقت تعليم نمي خواستي
Your dancing's not bad either.
رقص تو هم بد نيست
Oh my God, I'm terrible at this.
اوه خداي من. من تو اين کار افتضاحم
No, you just started, now come on, try and relax.
نه تو همين الان شروع کردي بيا تلاش کن و آروم باش
All right, here we go.
خوبه بريم
Now, this is much better.
حالا بهتر شد
This is just like any slow song.
اين خيلي آهنگه يواشيه
That's right, except in heels.
درسته به جز توي پاشنه ها
I tried to be a good dancer once.
من يکبار سعي کردم رقاص خوبي بشم
What happened?
چي شد؟
Have you ever been to a sober dance?
تا حالا به مرکز رقص رفتي؟
I hate to point this out but dancing is 90% beer.
متنفرم از اينکه بگم ولي رقصيدن 90% مشروب خوردنه
What about dirty dancing?
رقص کثيف چي؟
Wow, you're in a mood.
واي تو تو حسي
You're like a different person tonight.
مثل يه آدم ديگه شدي امشب
Well, I'm happy. I'm dating someone.
خب خوشحالم که با يکي هستم
That guy Andy is really hot.
اون آقا اندي خيلي جذابه
I guess.
فکر کنم
But uh... he's not my boyfriend.
ولي اون دوست پسرم نيست
You are.
تو هستي
Never did I know I'd feel the way I do.
# Never did I know I'd feel the way I do. #
You changed my life in so many ways.
# You changed my life in so many ways. #
And the moment that we kissed, you showed me...
# And the moment that we kissed, you showed me... #
You sure he said boyfriend?
مطمئني گفت دوست پسر؟
He didn't say, boy do I need a friend?
اون نگفت پسر. من به يه دوست نياز دارم؟
Yeah, I don't know what to say to him.
آره من نمي دونم چي بايد بهش بگم
You know I look at him sometimes and I have these feelings like...
مي دوني بعضي وقتا نگاش مي کنم و يه احساسي دارم
I cherish him, but then I always feel like I'm waiting...
انگار بهش احترام مي ذارم ولي بعد هميشه فکر مي کنم دارم منتظر مي مونم
for the other shoe to drop like it always has.
براي اتفاق بعدي
He seems to be moving awfully fast for a psychiatrist.
انگار خيلي داره تند پيش مي ره
I mean the whole idea of this romantic myth stuff is a recipe...
منظورم اينه که کل ايده ي اين مسائل رمانتيک يه راهي هست به
for disaster, he's a shrink, he should know this.
فاجعه بايد اينو بدونه
Yeah, he is a shrink.
آره
I think he knows more about this stuff than us.
فکر کنم بيشتر از ما بدونه
He has a degree, we just have Oprah.
اون درجه داره ما تازه اپرا گرفتيم
Oprah has made it impossible for me to have a close...
اپرا باعث شده که نتونم با کسي ارتباط نزديکي
relationship with anyone, besides Oprah.
داشته باشم
He's so normal and I'm just, I'm such a freak.
اون خيلي طبيعيه و من فقط يه احمقم
We're really different.
ما واقعا متفاوتيم
I think that's good.
فکر کنم خوبه
The thing about you gay guys is that you're just obsessed...
مشکل شما اينه که شما دوتا خسته شديد
with finding carbon copies of yourself.
از پيدا کردن شبيه به خودتون
At least with guys and girls we know we'll never figure...
حداقل با دخترا و پسرايي که هيچ وقت تصورش رو نمي کنيم
each other out so we just say, "Oh, he's just being a man"
براي همين فقط مي گيم اوه اون داره مردونگي اش رو نشون مي ده
or "Oh, she's just on the rag."
يا اوه اون درست روي فرشه
I guess.
حدس مي زنم
Have you had a fight yet?
دعوا هم کرديد؟
No.
نه
Is that weird?
عجيبه؟
Well you do have some things in common,
خب يه چيزايي بطور معمول داريد
he 'two-steps' and you 'twelve-step'.
اون دو تا گام و تو 12 گام
You know maybe your comedy is like my love life.
شايد کمدي شما مثل زندگي عشقي منه
You know if you stop trying so hard it will come, you know?
اگه اينقدر سخت نگيريد خودش مي آد
But fat jokes are my forte and being fat is the only...
ولي چاق بودن
funny thing that ever happened to me.
تنها چيز خنده داري بوده که برام اتفاق افتاده
It's the only... thing some idiot off the street...
تنها چيز يه احمق توي خيابون
would find interesting about me.
در مورد من جذب بشه
Who are these for?
اينا براي کيه؟
My friends Jeff and Jeff are bringing their new foster child.
دوستام جف و جف دارن فرزند خوانده شون رو مي آرن
Ah, kids.
آه بچه ها
I saw some of those on TV once.
من چند تايي رو توي تلويزيون ديدم
Ever think about having kids?
تا حالا به بچه داشتن فکر کرديد؟
No, I already have one, myself.
نه من خودم يکي دارم
I love children.
من عاشق بچه ام
I can't imagine anybody not loving kids.
نمي تونم تصور کنم کسي بچه دوست نداشته باشه
Would you stop it?
بس مي کني؟
Come here.
بيا اينجا
Hello.
سلام
Hi. I'm Michael.
سلام من مايکل هستم
So Steve tells me you used to be fat?
استيو بهم گفته که تو قبلا چاق بودي؟
Oh Adam told me you used to be short.
آدام هم به من گفته تو قبلا کوتاه بودي
Were you like fat or... circus fat?
چاق بودي يا خيلي چاق بودي؟
You know you really ought to be standing when you insult a lady.
مي دوني وقتي که داري به يه خانم توهين مي کني بايد ايستاده باشي
Oh, wait, you already are.
اوه صبر کن تو ايستادي
What did you do with all that loose skin,
با اون همه پوست شل شده چيکار کردي
did you like donate it to a burn unit or something?
به موسسه خيريه دادي؟
No, I gave it to the little people, the real little people,
نه دادمش به آدم کوتوله ها کوتوله هاي واقعي
not the fake little people like you.
نه کوتو له هاي الکي مثل تو
Wow.
واي
Cute kid, huh?
بچه بانمکيه . هان؟
Wonder if she's gay.
تصور مي کنم اونم هم جنس بازه
Look, I just wanted to let you know that I think it's cool...
ببين من فقط مي خواستم بدوني که من فکر مي کنم ايرادي نداره
that you and Steve are hanging out and you know,
اينکه تو و استيو داريد با هم بيرون مي ريد
doing your gay love thing.
و کارتون رو با عشق پيش مي بريد
Awe, thanks Michael, that's sweet.
ممنون مايکل لطف داري
Yeah.
آره
I just, you know before he met you he was such a whore.
قبل از اينکه با تو آشنا بشه خيلي مزخرف بود
Sorry, whore's get paid.
ببخشيد مزخرف ها حقوق مي گيرن
He was a slut.
اون گند بود
He used to go to like the gym every night and just go in...
اون دوست داشت بره به باشگاه و هر شب
the shower and hook up with like hundreds of guys,
فقط بره زير دوش و با صد تا مرد باشه
like the hottest guys in New York for the taking.
مثل جذاب ترين مردان نيويورک
To be honest with you, I can never really understand...
اگه بخوام باهات صادق باشم هيچ وقت درک نمي کنم
why he would like give up all that easy lovemaking,
چرا اين همه عشق هاي راحت رو از دست مي ده
but you know I understand that you,
ولي مي دوني من مي فهمم که تو
you know guys want equal rights, so.
تو مي دوني مردان حقوق برابر مي خوان
Your best friend is cute.
بهترين دوستت بانمکه
She's kind of a bitch though, right?
اون يه جورايي مشکل داره درسته؟
Yeah.
آره
What time do your folks get in?
رفقات ساعت چند مي آن ؟
They should be here in about an hour.
تقريبا يک ساعت ديگه
Did you put away Michael's porn?
تو عکساي مايکل رو کنار گذاشتي؟
Yeah.
آره
Did you put away Michael?
تو مايکل رو کنار گذاشتي؟
Oh, I hope they like me.
اوه اميدوارم از من خوششون بياد
Honey, you'll be fine.
عزيزم مشکلي پيش نمي آد
They're the ones that should be worried about what you think,
اونا بايد نگران طرز تفکر تو باشن
they're entering our world.
اونا دارن به دنياي ما وارد مي شن
When you're a born again Christian...
وقتي تو دوباره مسيحي متولد بشي
your world follows you.
دنياي تو دنبالت مي آد
Yeah, but they're not that religious anymore.
آره ولي اونا ديگه اونقدر مذهبي نيستند
Look, I've been out for ten years,
ببين من 10 ساله اومدم بيرون
they've had plenty of time to get used to the idea...
اونا به اندازه ي کافي فرصت داشتن که واقعيت رو بپذيرن
that eventually I'd meet somebody, huh?
اينکه بالاخره يکي رو ميبينم
Ew, Fags!
اي
Welcome to the West Village asshole, better get used to it!
خوش اومدي آشغال بهتره بهش عادت کني
Asshole.
آشغال
You know, Jesus was a Jew.
مي دوني مسيح يهودي بوده
That's right, he sure was.
درسته دقيقا بوده
Uh, would anybody care for some wine?
کسي مشروب مي خواد؟
That would be delightful.
عالي خواهدبود
Open that box of Zinfandel we brought.
اون جعبه رو که آورديم باز کن
Show him what we bought at the airport.
ببين که چي آورديم به فرودگاه
Now it's not for dinner, it's just for decoration.
براي شام نيست فقط براي تزئيناته
It was made from actual ceramic chips recovered from the site.
از سراميک اصل ساخته شده بود
Here we go.
بريم
Mom, dad, here we are.
مامان بابا ما اومديم
Don't you want some?
نمي خواي؟
Oh, no I'm an alcoholic.
من الکل مصرف نمي کنم
He's in recovery.
داره ترک مي کنه
Excuse us for a minute, mom, dad.
ما رو ببخشيد مامان و بابا
I feel like I have a sign under my neck that reads,
فکر مي کنم يه نشونه زير گردنم دارم که مي گه
"I eat your son's ass".
من حال پسرتون رو مي گيرم
Look, stop it, just act like you normally do, okay?
ببين. بس کنيد طبيعي رفتار کن
We have to show them that there's nothing wrong with being gay.
بايد بهشون ثابت کنيم که هم جنس بازي هيچ مشکلي نداره
Look, they're in New York now, not Texas.
ببين اونا الان در نيو يورک هستن نه تکزاس
Good lordy these windows are so big!
اين پنجره ها عجب بزرگن
I feel like I could just fall right out.
فکر کردم همين الان مي افتم بيرون
Not exactly a ton of privacy though is there?
دقيقا اينجا خصوصي نيست. هست؟
Mom, dad, I just wanted to say that normally Adam and I are...
مامان و بابا مي خواستم بگم که من و آدام
very affectionate with each other and we don't feel that...
خيلي با هم راحتيم و احساس نمي کنيم که
it would be fair to us, or really to you if we behaved in a way...
برامون منصفانه است يا براي شما اگه طوري رفتار مي کرديم
that somehow demonstrated that we are in any way ashamed...
که نشون بده ما ذره اي شرمنده ايم
of our feelings for each other.
براي احساساتمون نسبت به همديگه
I think it's important that we express our normal healthy...
فکر کنم که مهمه که سلامتي خودمون رو
affection for each other in your presence.
و احساسمون رو نسبت به هم در حضور شما بروز بديم
Right? And um, um...
درسته؟ و ام
Well, I just wanted to say that.
خب من فقط مي خواستم اينا رو بگم
Oh, well.
اوه خوبه
Don't not be ya'lls usual selves, just cause we're here!
نمي خوايم فقط چون اينجاييم نقش معمولي بودن رو بازي کنيم
Yes.
بله
We're all grown ups here.
ما همه اينجا بالغيم
Ew, fags!
اي
So how would a person find curtains for...
خب چطوري براي چنين پنجره اي پرده
a window so big, son?
پيدا مي کنن پسرم؟
Well, you know, New York is a very big city so...
خب مي دوني نيويورک شهر بزرگيه
How's that wine, any left?
اون مشروب چطور بود. چيزي مونده؟
We don't have any more boxes of wine,
ديگه نداريم
I can open an actual bottle.
مي تونم يه بطري اصل رو باز کنم
Got it, right here.
گرفتمش همين جا
Ah, I'm never having sex again.
من ديگه ارتباطي نخواهم داشت
No, they'll be fine.
نه اونا خوب پيش  مي رن
No, they really liked you.
نه اونا واقعا تو رو دوست داشتن
As your dad was leaving he told me I was going to hell.
وقتي پدرت داشت مي رفت گفت داره مي ره به جهنم
Yeah, well he only tries to save the people he likes.
آره اون فقط سعي مي کنه که اونايي که دوست داره نجات بده
How come you never talk about your family?
چرا هيچ وقت از خانواده ات نمي گي؟/
What are they, in the witness protection program or something?
چي شده اونا کجان توي برنامه مجرمين؟
Uh, my family is really weird.
خانواده ي من واقعا عجيبن
They're not lucky.
شانس ندارن
Adam, there's no such thing as luck, okay?
آدام شانسي وجود نداره باشه؟
Ah, yeah, there is.
چرا هست
Listen if you want to meet them you can...
ببين اگه مي خواي باهاشون ملاقات داشته باشي
come with me to Hannukah dinner in a few months.
مي توني بياي به هوناکا چند ماه ديگه
If you still like me.
اگه هنوز دوستم داري
If I still like you?
اگه هنوز دوست دارم؟
Yeah, I know I'm just making an assumption there.
مي دونم که دارم يه فرضيه مي سازم
Adam, come on.
آدام بس کن
I more than like you.
من بيشتر از اينکه دوست داشته باشم
- Adam... - I love you.
آدام من عاشقتم
You just had to say it first, didn't you?
مي تونستي همون اول بگي نمي تونستي؟
I'm sorry, it's easier for me to say it than to hear it.
معذرت مي خوام برام گفتنش راحت تر از شنيدنشه
Adam, I love you.
آدام من دوست دارم
I love you.
من دوست دارم
Adam, I do, I love you.
آدام من واقعا دوست دارم
Hey, it's Steve, I am ridiculously in love
هي اين استيو من به طرز مزخرفي عاشق شدم
and therefore extremely unreachable,
و براي همين واقعا در دسترس نيستم
but leave a message and I'll get back to you.
ولي پيغام بذاريد و من جوابتون رو مي دم
All right, this next comic used to be really fat.
خب اين قبلا خيلي چاق بود
no one's ever been in there.
چون هيچ کس تا به حال اونجا نبوده
She's the hottest female comic this side of...
اون جذاب ترين زنيه که
I can't think of any hot female comics.
من نمي تونم به زنهاي جذاب فکر کنم
But even if you don't think she's funny, and she's not,
ولي اگه تو فکر کني که خنده دار نيست پس نيست
then just turn her around and look upon Rhonda Gernan...
پس برش گردون و به روندا جرنن نگاه کن
and her amazing heart shaped ass.
و هيکل جذابش
Thank you. Wow.
ممنون واي
You know, Lou, I always knew you were crazy,
مي دوني لو من هميشه مي دونستم که تو ديوونه اي
but in those pants I can see your nuts and they're sad.
ولي مي تونم ناراحتيت رو ببينم
They're sad because there's no one up there.
ناراحتن
Lou's so small. Ask me how small he is?
خيلي کوچيکه
How small is he?
چقد رکوچيک؟
Knock, knock.
تق تق
Who's there?
کي اونجاست؟
Oh, I don't see anything, I guess it's Lou's penis.
اوه هيچي نمي بينم
Well obviously there's one man in the audience...
خب حداقل يکي توي اين جمع هست که
who's secure enough with his masculinity...
امنيت داشته باشه
to laugh at my jokes.
تا به جک هاي من بخنده
Hey. Thanks for coming.
هي ممنونم که اومدي
Oh yeah.
اوه آره
And laughing.
و مي خندي
Yeah, hi.
آره سلام
You're, you're funny.
تو خنده داري
I just got fired.
همين الان کباب شدم
All Lou did was complement you on your ass,
لو فقط حالتو جاورد
why did you make fun of him?
چرا مسخر ه اش کردي؟
Because in this heart shaped ass is an asshole...
چون توي اين عکس چيزي هست که من
which is, I guess, what I am.
فکر مي کنم که منم
Gross.
چندش
It's good to see you have fun with Gloria Steinam here.
خوشحالم که مي بينمت تو اينجا با گلوريا خوش مي گذروني
You know I'm not with her, she just sat next to me.
مي دوني من باهاش نيستم اون فقط کنارم نشسته
I'm not your mother.
من مامانت نيستم
Oh, well you kind of look like her.
اوه خوب تويه جورايي شبيه بهش هستي
Well, that's good.
خب خوبه
I'm late I've got to go stare into a black hole.
ديرم شده بايد برم
You know I don't see Steve as often as I used to...
مي دوني استيو رو مثل قبل نمي بينم
ever since he hooked up with Adam.
از وقتي که با آدام مي پلکه
I think they're completely wrong for each other.
فکر کنم اونا کاملا نا مناسبن براي همديگه
Don't you agree?
موافقي؟
Oh, come on their fags!
اوه اونا
You know how it is.
مي دوني که چه طورين
Besides I think it's good, Adam's luck has completely
در ضمن من فکر مي کنم خوبه که شانس آدام بالاخره
changed since they met. Why am I talking to you?
از وقتي که همديگه رو ديدن فرق کرده
Hey, you want to get a drink or something?
نوشيدني مي خواي؟
Like, it's so early.
انگار خيلي زوده
I try not to drink.
سعي مي کنم مشروب نخورم
You don't get thirsty? You know your body is 90% water.
تشنه ات نمي شه ؟ مي دوني 90% بدنت آبه
Oh, right.
او آره
Are there carbohydrates in pot?
توي قابلمه کربوهيدرات هست؟
Oh.
اوه
Wow, public access.
واي
Do you believe they get away with that?
باورت مي شه که با اون کنار اومدن؟
Oh, hey look, American Movie Classics.
اوه ببين فيلم هاي آمريکايي کلاسيک
You like that don't you?
دوستش داري مگه نه؟
Isn't it funny how the only requirements for them to be...
خنده دار نيست که تنها احتياجات اونا
a classic is that it be over 40 years old.
يه فيلم کلاسيکه که 40 ساله پيش بوده
I never thought of that.
من هيچ وقت به اين فکر نکردم
You're funny.
تو خنده داري
Funny lady.
خانم خنده دار
Oh my God, I love that movie.
اوه خداي من من اين فيلم رو دوست دارم
Oh my God me too, Steve makes me watch it all the time,
اوه منم خداي من! استيو منو مجبور مي کنه هميشه تماشاش کنم
except I think 'Funny Girl' is much more satisfying.
مگر اينکه فکر کنم دختر خنده دار جالب تر باشه
Well, I think that's the common opinion.
خب فکر کنم اين نظره شخصيه
Yeah, that's the common opinion...
آره
Mmmm.
اهمم
I've got the munchies.
من مانچي ها رو دارم
My God what are you doing, I can't eat that!
خداي من داري چيکار مي کني من نمي تونم بخورمش
Oh, you can't have one pie?
اوه تونمي توني يه پاي رو بخوري؟
No I can't have one pie!
نه که نمي تونم
One pie is like an appetizer to me.
يه پاي مثل محرک اشتهاست براي من
I eat that, I unleash the beast!
من مي خورمش
Well then come on Rhonda, unleash the beast!
خب بيا روندا
I had a slip.
من يه تيکه خوردم
- Thanks gents, have a good night. - Thank you.
ممنون آقايون شب خوبي داشته باشيد ممنون
All right, okay.
باشه
Ah, you know I don't think this is such a good idea.
خب فکر نمي کنم اين کار خوبي باشه
What is the big deal? Look you met my parents...
خب که چي؟ ببين تو خانواده ي منو ديدي
I want to meet yours.
من مي خوام مال تو رو ببينم
All I'm saying is that they're...
تنها چيزي که من مي گم اينه که اونا
I know, I know they're not lucky.
مي دونم مي دونم خوش شانس نيستن
They're kind of cursed.
آره يه جورايي
Well if they're anything as dramatic as their son Adam,
خوب اگه چيزي مثل پسرشون باشن
focus, okay, relax.
تمرکز کن باشه آروم باش
You always exaggerate everything.
توهمي چيز رو هميشه بزرگ مي کني
Go.
برو
Okay?
باشه
Hello.
سلام
We're here.
ما اينجائيم
Welcome home!
به خونه خوش اومدي
Darn it, we just replaced that thing last week.
ما اونو هفته پيش درستش کرديم
Happy Hannukah.
هانوکا مبارک
Whoa!
واي
You must be Steve.
تو بايداستيو باشي
Hi.
سلام
Welcome, welcome, welcome, welcome.
خوش آمديد
I'm Adam's father, I'm Norm and this is Sherry and this is...
من پدر آدام هستم. من نرم هستم اين شري و اين هم
our beautiful daughter Ruth.
دختر زيبامون روت هست
Hi, it's so nice to meet... Ooh!
سلام. از اشنايي تون خوشحالم اووه
Uh-oh, did you bite your tongue again sweetie?
اوه دوباره زبونت رو گاز گرفتي عزيزم؟
Mm-hmm.
اهمم
Hi.
سلام
Hi, Ruth, Mr., Mrs. Bernstein.
سلام روت . خانم و آقاي برنشتين
Thank you for having me.
ممنون از پذيرائي تون
Please call me Sherry, any boyfriend of Adam's...
خواهش مي کنم منو شري صدا کنيد دوست پسر آدام
is a boyfriend of mine.
دوست پسر منم هست
And that's right.
و اشکالي نداره
It's getting a little rare having this one come around...
يه کمي بنظر کمياب مي رسه اين دور و برا اومديد
and visit us once in awhile.
و چند وقت يه بار بيا بهمون سر بزن
I think he's just a little embarrassed...
فکر مي کنه که يه خورده خجالت زده شده
about the Bernstein curse.
در مورد برنشتين
Dad, there is no such thing.
پدر چنين چيزي وجود نداره
You like that? Are you enjoying?
تو دوست داري؟ داري لذت ي بري؟
Mmm.
همم
Steve, matza?
استيو؟
Oh, yes, thank you very much sir.
اوه بله خيلي ممنونم جناب
Thank you.
ممنون
Seven more.
هفت تا ديگه
I thought that was shatter proof.
فکر کردم نمي شکنه
All right.
باشه
I'm sorry, I just have to ask this,
معذرت مي خوام ولي بايد بپرسم اينو
but are all of you okay with this?
ولي هيچ کدوم از شما ديگه مشکلي نداريد؟
Well, I used to charge people a quarter...
خب من عادت داشتم که به مردم هر دفعه که سوال مي کردن
every time they asked us that question,
يه سکه بهشون بدم
but nobody could afford it.
ولي هيچ کس توانش رو نداشت
Lowered it to a nickel and it still broke practically...
اونو به يا نيکل رسوند و هنوز تقريبا ورشکسته اس
everybody's bank.
بانک همه
Happiness is accepting life on life's terms.
خوشبختي زندگي رو توي بخشهاي مختلف مي پذيره
You know I mean no matter what they happen to be.
مي دوني منظورم چيه مهم نيست که اونا چي مي شن
You just do your best with what you've been given.
تو با چيزي که بهت داده شده بهترين تلاشتو ن
Till we found out we were luck challenged,
تا وقتي فهميديم که با شانس مقابله مي کنيم
We were on 'In Search Of' in the 70s...
ما داشتيم مال دهه 70 رو جستجو مي کرديم
Oh, we still have the tape, we'll show it to you...
خب ما هنوز فيلمشو داريم نشونت مي دم
after we light the menorah.
بعد از اينکه روشنش کنيم
Mom, could we get through a Hannukah...
مامان مي تونيم از اين بگذريم
without watching that tape?
بدون تماشاي اون فيلم؟
Adam just hates that tape, he was a real pizza face...
آدام از اون فيلم متنفره اون واقعا يه صورت پيتزايي داره توش
back then you know.
اون وقتا
Too busy with all that white face paint to clear.
خيلي مشغول پاک کردن اون صورت بزرگ رنگي بود
Anybody want coffee?
کسي قهوه نمي خواد؟
White face paint?
با رنگ صورت؟
I was a goth in high school.
من توي دبيرستان يه گت بودم
Who would like coffee?
کي قهوه مي خواد؟
Oh!
اوه
Well, we're out of coffee.
خب قهوه مون تموم شده
Uh, it's okay, it's kind of late for coffee anyway.
اشکالي نداره ديگه براي قهوه خوردن ديره
You know what?
مي دوني چيه؟
Let's spin the draidle and open presents.
بذاريد کادوها رو باز کنيم
Yeah!
آره
Well, now that you have a special friend
خب حالا که يه دوست خوب داري
I want to see more of you around here.
مي خواستم اينجا بيشتر ببينمت
Dad!
پدر
Steve is Adam's lover. God, you are so square.
استيو عاشق آدامه
Oh, it was such a pleasure to meet you Steve... oh, thank you.
اوه خوشحالم از ديدارتون استيو ممنون
I'm so happy that my Adam has found someone as nice as you.
خيلي خوشحالم که آدام من يکي به خوبي شما پيدا کرده
Oh, Sherry, look thanks for making me feel so welcome,
اوه شري نگاه کن. ممنونم از پذيرايي تون
and oh, for such an amazing meal.
و براي يه چنين غذاي خوشمزه اي
Well, it was made with love.
خب با عشق پخته شده
You know, I hate to see you waste money
مي دوني متنفرم از اينکه ولخرجي مي کني
taking a taxi to the train station.
تا ايستگاه مترو تاکسي مي گيري
Don't you want us to give you a ride?
نمي خواي بذاري ما برسونيمت؟
No!
نه
Thank you, no.
ممنون نه
I love you.
دوستت دارم
Why can't a lesbian diet and put on makeup...
چرا يه هم جنس باز نمي تونه رژيم بگيره و آرايش کنه
at the same time?
همزمان؟
I don't know, why?
نمي دونم چرا؟
Cause you can't eat Jenny Craig with Mary Kay on your face.
چون تا وقتي جني کريگ و ماري کي روي صورتتن نمي توني چيزي بخوري
Does anyone know what mothballs smell like?
کسي مي دونه نفتالين چه بويي مي ده؟
Yes.
آره
Oh really, how did you get them to spread their little legs?
اوه واقعا چطور تونستي وادارشون کني که پاهاشون رو جدا کنن؟
I have an audition for a lesbian cruise ship...
من يه حضور توي يه کشتي سرعتي همجنس بازي دارم
next week, very excited about it.
هفته ديگه در موردش هيجان زده ام
I like lesbians, lesbians like me.
من همجنس بازا رو دوست دارم . مثل خودم
Trying to cut down on the fat jokes though.
البته مي خوام که شوخي هاي بيمزه در مورد چاقي رو تموم کنم
Mm, I still can't even imagine you fat.
من هنوزم نمي تونم تو رو چاق تصور کنم
Oh, I can, oh, honey, show Steve that photo of you.
اوه مي تونم. عزيزم اون عکستو به استوي نشون بده
No!
نه
Yeah, come on.
آره بيا
No, I look like a Long Island blimp...
نه من مثل يه تپه ي بزرگ توي جزيره ي لانگ مي مونم
with a bad Chinese lady perm.
با يه زن چيني
No.
نه
Speaking of Long Island, you know we went to Long Island...
مي گي جزيره هاي لانگ. ما رفتيم اونجا
last week, we went to Adam's parents' house.
هفته پيش رفتيم به خونه پدر و مادر آدام
Oh my God, I was there once and a piece of space lab...
اوه خداي من ، يه دفعه که اونجا بودم يه تيکه از مواد آزمايشگاهي
splashed down into their pool.
افتاد توي استخرشون
Oh my God!
اوه خداي من
Actually...
در واقع
I'm going to ask Adam to marry me.
مي خوام از آدام درخواست ازدواج کنم
Oh my God!
اوه خداي من
You're going to marry him!
مي خواي باهاش ازدواح کني
But you guys have only been going out for a couple months.
ولي شماها فقط چند ماهه که با هم آشنا شديد
Actually it's almost been a year Michael,
در واقع تقريبا يکسال شده مايکل
besides my parents got married on the third date...
درضمن پدر و مادرم توي سومين ملاقات با هم ازدواج کردند
and they're still together.
و هنوزم با هم هستند
Well you're only as monogamous as your options.
خب تو توي گزينه هات خيلي محدود فکر مي کني
I mean your parents live in a trailer park in a field.
منظور من اينه که پدر و مادرت توي يه باغ زندگي مي کنن
Excuse me!
ببخشيد
Only as monogamous as their options!
به اندازه ي فکرشون محدودن
You know it gets worse Michael, I'm going to ask him to move in.
مي دوني که بدتر مي شه مايکل مي خوام ازش بخوام بياد اينجا زندگي کنه
Oh my God!
اوه خداي من
I knew this day was going to come.
مي دونستم که اين روز مي رسه
You know you said you needed a place to crash for the night...
تو گفتي که يه جايي رو مي خواي که شبا بموني
and you've been living on my couch for five years.
و پنج ساله که روي مبلم خوابيدي
Jesus, Michael, be happy for them.
خداي من مايکل براي اونا خوشحال باش
I think it's great.
من فکر مي کنم عاليه
He's going to flip out.
اون از خوشحالي بال در مي آره
He really loves you.
اون واقعا دوست داره
I love him too, I do.
منم دوسش دارم
You know it's funny when I was a kid I just supposed I'd get
مي دونم جالبه که وقتي بچه بودم تصور مي کردم با هر
married like everybody else, but I don't know,
ديگه اي ازدواج کنم ولي نمي دونم
turned out I was gay and I just figured it wasn't in the cards.
انگار که هم جنس باز از آب در اومدم و فکر کردم توي گزينه هام نبوده
But I mean I don't even know what I think of marriage anyway.
ولي بعدش فکر کردم که اصلا نمي دونم ازدواج يعني چي
Sometimes I think it's a dying institution.
گاهي اوقات فکر مي کنم که يه موسسه مرگ و ميره
Yeah, well it is, then you fall in love.
آره ولي وقتيه که عاشق مي شي
Exactly.
دقيقا
Sometimes I look at him and I think,
بعضي وقتا بهش نگاه مي کنم و فکر مي کنم
this is not the person I was supposed to end up with,
اين آدمي نبود که قرار بوده باهاش تا آخر عمر باشم
but I don't know, somehow it's all okay.
ولي نمي دونم چرا يه جورايي همه چيز خوب پيش رفته
So who gets to wear the dress?
خب کي مي تونه لباس رو بپوشه؟
You do.
تو
Hi.
سلام
Hey, good lookin'.
هي خوش تيپ شدي
Wait a minute, come here, come here.
يه لحظه صبر کن بيا اينجا
I um, I want to take you someplace. Okay?
من مي خوام ببرمت يه جايي باشه؟
Oh God, please don't tell me there's something...
اوه خداي من خواهش مي کنم نگو که يه جاييه که
called three stepping.
بهش مي گن سه مرحله اي
No, it's just my favorite place in the city.
نه جاي مورد علاقه من در شهر هست
You game?
بازي مي کني؟
Yeah.
آره
- Let's go. - Okay.
بريم باشه
The Brooklyn Bridge, that's your favorite place?
پل بروکلين جاي مورد علاقه ات هست؟
Uh huh.
آهان
Let's go, come on, come on!
بريم . بيا بيا
God, I haven't been here in years,
خداي من چندين ساله اينجا نيومدم
it's getting harder to remember where the towers were, you know?
داره سخت مي شه که يادم بياد برجها کجا مي دون
You were in New York on that day, what was it like?
تو اون روز نيو يورک بودي. چطور بود؟
Oh, I don't know, it was just crazy.
اوه نمي دونم. فقط مزخرف بود
These are crazy times, makes things like, I don't know,
اين زمانهاي مزخرفن که يه جورايي باعث مي شن بگي نمي دونم
security, commitment, more important.
امنيت ، اعتزاض، اهميت بيشتر
I can't believe that you brought me here.
باورم نميشه که منو آوردي اينجا
My drug problem began on this very spot.
مشکل اعتيادم درست در همين نقطه شروع شد
Well, no, actually it began at Danceateria,
خب نه در واقع در ترياي رقص شروع شد
this club in the 80's.
باشگاه 80
This go-go boy coke head with big old like Dee Snyder hair.
ياروي گنده که مي گفت برو برو مثل دي سنايدر پير بود
He was part of some dance troop, what was it called?
اون عضو يه گروه رقص بود. اسمش چي بود؟
Oh, the Dazzle Dancers.
اوه رقاصاي دزل
Well he fed me my first hit of blow and we went back to
خب اون اولين پک رو به من داد و رفت به
my place and he shit right in front of me, all over my carpet.
خونه ام و اون هر دو تا جلوي چشمام گند زدن
Oh, my place looked like something out of
اوه خونه ام شده مثل يه جايي مثل
Willy Wonka after he left.
ويلي ونکا بعد از اينکه رفت
Oh, and he was singing some song from the...
داشت يه شعر از ... مي خوند
what was it from?
از چي بود؟
Like the Sound of Music.
مثل صداي موسيقي
Oh my God, how could I have forgotten that?
اوه خداي من چطور ممکنه که اونو فراموش کرده باشم؟
Oh my God.
اوه خداي من
Honey.
عزيزم
I have to get out of here, all I can see is disaster.
من بايد از اينجا برم هرچي که مي بينم يه فاجعه است
No, disaster!
فاجعه اي در کار نيست
I need time to think Adam!
من به زمان براي فکر احتياج دارم آدام
Time to think!
زمان براي فکر
Think!
فکر
Where are you going?
کجا داري مي ري؟
So he just ran away yelling "disaster"?
خب يعني اون داشت فرياد مي زد فاجعه و فرار کرد؟
Yeah.
آره
We were talking about the World Trade Center...
ما داشتيم در مورد در مورد مرکز تجارت جهاني حرف مي زديم
and what happened and he just freaked out.
و اونچه که اتفاق افتاده بعدش اون ترسيد
Well, he is a doctor in New York City.
خب اون يه دکتره توي نيويورک
He was in Province Town on 9/11.
در شهر پرونيس خيابان 9/11 بوده
Well, he'll call you when he's ready.
وقتي که اماده بشه صدات مي کنه
Everybody gets the jitters before.
همه قبلش همين طور مي شن
Before what?
قبل از چي؟
The next big terrorist attack.
حمله بزرگ تروريستس بعدي
Uh!
آه
Oh!!
اوه
He just dumped me!
اون همين الان منو ضايع کرد
What!
چي
In the shower.
توي دوش
Oh my God!
اوه خداي من
There ain't no God!
خدايي نيست
Did he say why?
گفت چرا؟
Just that, he wasn't ready...
فقط اينکه آماده نيست
and he said I didn't really know who he was!
و گفت که واقعا نمي دونه کي هست
Oh my God, why is this happening?
اوه خداي من اين چرا داره اتفاق مي افته؟
You know, you date...
مي دوني چطور شما قرار مي ذاريد
You look for the person who has the least amount of flaws...
دنبال کسي مي گردي که کمترين وجه اختلافي داشته باشيد
and then you find someone who you think is about...
و بعد يه نفرو پيدا مي کني که فکر مي کني قراره
as perfect as you can get.
بهترين حالت رو داشته باشي
Oh, but of course there's no such thing as perfection.
البته چنين چيزي به طور مطلق وجود نداره
Why do people project this image of themselves...
چرا مردم چنين تصويري از خودشون نشون مي دن که
that's like completely opposite from who they are?
کاملا با اون چيزي که هستن متفاوته؟
Maybe they're just afraid they won't be...
شايد مي ترسن که
loved for who they really are.
بعنوان کسي که ستن دوست داشته نشن
But that's crazy.
ولي مزخرفه
I mean you come home one day and you think you know this person...
انگار يه روز مي آي و فکر مي کني که اين يارو رو مي شناسي
and then all of a sudden you realize you do not...
و بعد يک دفعه متوجه مي شي که
know this person from Adam.
تو اين آدم رو به اسم آدام نمي شناسي
I need to speak with Steven Hicks.
من بايد با استيون هيکس حرف بزنم
Are you one of his patients?
يکي از بيماراش هستيد
Don't make me go Shirley McClaine on you.
نذار حالتو جا بيارم
You better give that guy some closure or he's going to...
بهتره به اون يارو يه چيزي بگي وگرنه نه
wind up in here in a body cast.
من تورو اينجا توي يه تابوت مي پيچونم
Look, look, I appreciate you standing up for your friend,
ببين ببين من تو رو درک مي کنم که داري از دوستت دفاع مي کني
but I did give Adam closure, all right?
ولي من به آدام نزديک شدم درسته؟
In a shower stall.
توي دوش حمام
All right, okay, I admit it was perhaps a little abrupt...
باشه قبول . اعتراف مي کنم شايد يه کم تند رفتم
but what in the world...
ولي توي دنيا
One minute you're telling me you want to marry him,
يه دقيقه بهم مي گي که مي خواي باهام ازدواج کني
all that bullshit about commitment...
همه اون مزخرفات در مورد تعهد داشتن
and you're a total slut.
تو کاملا مزخرفي
There are things about me you just don't know, all right?
چيزايي در مورد من هست که تو نمي دوني
Like what?
مثل چي؟
Like... we just aren't right for each other.
مثل اينکه ما براي هم مناسب نيستيم
We...
ما
He doesn't really love me.
اون واقعا منو دوست نداره
We were co-dependent and then...
ما به هم وابسته بوديم و بعد
There are things about being co-de,
درمورد وابستگي حرف زياده
it's called depending on another person.
منظور وابسته بودن به يک شخص خاصيه
You act like you're so grown up like you're so above it,
طوري رفتار مي کني که انگار بزرگ شدي
but you're an asshole and a baby.
ولي تو يه آشغالي
You're an asshole who's also a baby!
تويه آشغالي که بچه هم هست
I'm getting marriage advice from some gay whore, great.
من دارم پيشنهاد  ازدواج از يه همجنس باز مي شنوم. عالي
All right, let me get this straight.
باشه بذار ببينم چي شده
You meet Adam in 1987.
تو آدام رو در سال 1987 ملاقات کردي
You turn him into a coke head and then you poop on him.
اونو تبديل به يه معتاد کردي و بعدش هم عقب کشيدي
All in the same night?
همه تو همون يک شب؟
It wasn't my fault.
تقصير من نبود
It was cut with...
با ملين بچه گونه
baby laxative.
قاطي شده بود
I've had some bad dates but nothing like,
من چند تا دوست داشتم ولي
you know, biohazard.
هيچي مثل بيهوزارد نبود
How could we have dated for so long...
چطور تونستيم اين همه با هم بوده باشيم
and never recognized each other?
و هيچ وقت متوجه همديگه نشده باشيم؟
Oh, it was the 80s, it was a long time ago.
اوه دوره 80 بود خيلي وقت پيش
You know you're like Simon LeBon, in a boat,
مي دوني چيه تو مثل سايمون لبون هستي توي يه قايق
looking through the jungle for the cat lady and you know...
توي جنگل دنبال زن گربه اي مي گردي و
he was like the guy with a fiddle and the suspenders singing;
مي دوني اون مثل اون يارو با کمانچه هست و خواننده اي که مي خونه
"Come On Eileen".
بيا ايلين
Or you could just...
يا مي توني فقط
You could tell him who you were.
مي توني بهش بگي تو کي بودي
No, no Michael. No, he can't find out.
نه نه مايکل نه اون نمي تونه بفهمه
Michael don't you dare say a word to him, or Rhonda.
مايکل جرات داري يه کلمه به اون يا به روندا بگي
Michael, do you hear me?
مايکل مي شنوي؟
I told you, I don't know, I just know that he said...
همين الان بهت گفتم که نمي دونم فقط مي دونم که گفت
Adam isn't the one.
آدام اوني نيست که مي خواد
- Michael. - What?
مايکل چي؟
Michael, is that the whole story?
مايکل اين همه داستانه؟
Well, there's the other thing.
خب يه چيز ديگه هم هست
What?
چي؟
What other thing, Michael.
چه چيز ديگه اي مايکل
About Adam and Steve.
درباره آدام و استيو
It's kind of gross, I think I should tell you after dinner.
يه خورده چندشه فکر مي کنم که بايد بعد از شام بهت بگم
Why?
چرا؟
What do you know Michael?
تو چي مي دوني مايکل؟
Ahhhhh!
آه
And uh, then he broke up with me... in the shower.
و آهان...بعدش توي حموم باهام بهم زد
Steve was the go-go dancer!
استيو دمدمي مزاج بود
Excuse me, this is a private meeting.
ببخشيد اين يه ملاقات خصوصيه
Silence, sober one!
ساکت باش
What go-go dancer.
چي
The Hershey squirtin' coke head!
آشغال معتاد
Excuse me, you are challenging our serenity.
ببخشيد شما داريد با آرامشت مواجه مي شيد
Shut up!
خفه شو
Wait, from the 80's?
صبر کن ، از 80 تاش؟
Willy Wonka?
ويلي ونکا؟
Oh, my God.
اوه خداي من
Adam! Steve loves you, he just can't get past his humiliation...
آدام! استيو تو رو دوست داره فقط نمي تونه با احساس حقارتش کنار بياد
over the diarrhea thing and for turning you into...
نمي تونه با موضوع اينکه تو رو
some gay John Belushi.
به يه هم جنس باز تبديل کرده کنار بياد
That's why he broke up with you!
براي همينه که باهات بهم زد
But that is crazy.
ولي اين مزخرفه
God, you're right, he is totally unaware for a shrink.
تو راست مي گي اون واقعا خبر نداره داره چيکار مي کنه
I'm telling you, they're like preacher's kids.
دارم بهت مي گم اونا مثل بچه ها هستن
Cross talking is not allowed.
صحبت در گوشي نداريم
Mary, please!
ماري خواهش مي کنم
He's so confused.
اون خيلي سردرگمه
No, he's just an asshole and a baby.
نه اون فقط يه آشغاله بچه اس
He's a baby who's also an asshole.
اون يه بچه است که تازه آشغال هم هست
- Where are you going? - Ah!
کجا مي ري؟ آه؟
Adam, if you imagine it, you can achieve it.
آدام اگه تو فکرشو کني مي توني بدستش بياري
If you dream it, you could become it.
اگه روياش رو ببيني مي توني همون بشي
They said the good ones are always taken.
# They said the good ones are always taken. #
But I know that that's not true.
# But I know that that's not true. #
Cause if the good ones are always taken,
# Cause if the good ones are always taken, #
then how, oh how did I find you?
# then how, oh how did I find you? #
Well...
# Well... #
you're walking down the street happy as a pig in mud.
# you're walking down the street happy as a pig in mud. #
Feeling simple and sweet...
# Feeling simple and sweet... #
like a heifer chewing her cud.
# like a heifer chewing her cud. #
Now I don't want to burst your bubble...
# Now I don't want to burst your bubble... #
and make you fret.
# and make you fret. #
But I think that I smell trouble so watch your step.
# But I think that I smell trouble so watch your step. #
If you're raring to go and hopping back in the saddle.
# If you're raring to go and hopping back in the saddle. #
Next thing you know up a creek without a paddle.
# Next thing you know up a creek without a paddle. #
If you think you want success and all its trappings.
# If you think you want success and all its trappings. #
But honey, life's a mess, shit happens.
# But honey, life's a mess, shit happens.
They say that a life is just a bowl of cherries.
# They say that a life is just a bowl of cherries. #
But they don't make greeting cards...
# But they don't make greeting cards... #
about dingleberries.
# about dingleberries. #
Now you're embarrassed and you won't let no one see you,
# Now you're embarrassed and you won't let no one see you, #
'cause they don't write love songs about diarrhea.
# 'cause they don't write love songs about diarrhea. #
You've got a foot in tomorrow and foot in yesterday.
# You've got a foot in tomorrow and foot in yesterday. #
Not bad for a Dazzle Dancer.
Not bad for a Dazzle Dancer.
You'll get nothing but sorrow...
# You'll get nothing but sorrow... #
cause you're crapping on today.
# cause you're crapping on today. #
No matter what, you got to keep on laughing.
# No matter what, you got to keep on laughing. #
Just laugh with your mouth shut, cause shit happens.
# Just laugh with your mouth shut, cause shit happens. #
You doing in it and you're barefoot stepping in it.
# You doing in it and you're barefoot stepping in it. #
Thinking got a master plan,
# Thinking got a master plan, #
then it all just hits the fan.
# then it all just hits the fan. #
Life can throw you for a loop.
# Life can throw you for a loop. #
Then it covers you in poop.
# Then it covers you in poop. #
Shit happens.
# Shit happens. Shit happens. #
You ain't listening to me,
# You ain't listening to me, #
then my gums are just flapping.
# then my gums are just flapping. #
The moral of this story, shit happens.
# The moral of this story, shit happens. #
What?
# What? #
Shit!
# Shit! #
Huh?
# Huh? #
Can't hear you.
# Can't hear you. #
Shit!
# Shit! #
Shit, shit, shit, shit, shit!
# Shit, shit, shit, shit, shit! #
Life's a game and you can win it even when you're knee deep in it.
# Life's a game and you can win it even when you're knee deep in it. #
Keep a fighting and scrappin'...
# Keep a fighting and scrappin'... #
cause its spraying and splattin'...
# cause its spraying and splattin'... #
shit happens.
# shit happens. #
Yeah!
آره
Adam, Adam, wait up.
آدام آدام صبر کن
Adam, I'm sorry okay.
آدام معذرت مي خوام خوب؟
I have nothing to say to you.
چيزي ندارم بهت بگم
Look, I felt like I created this cocaine monster and unleashed
ببين من فکر کردم که من اين غول کوکائين رو ساختم
him onto the gay community to wreak havoc on midgets.
و اونو به جامعه همجنس بازها راه دادم
Adam, look... I gave you your first bump of coke.
آدام ببين. من اولين بار بهت مواد دادم
I...
من
I became incontinent in front of you.
من جلوي تو بيهوش شدم
Became incontinent?
بيهوش شدي؟
God, you are such an old lady.
خداي من، شما خانم پيري هستيد
You're just embarrassed.
خجالت کشيدي
Yes, all right, yes I am.
بله باشه . هستم
I'd be happy to course through life having a lover who thought...
من خوشحال مي شم که در زندگي عشقي که داشتم هيچ وقت
I never went to the bathroom at all.
به حموم نرفتم
Who thought that some little dove just came...
اوني که فکر کرد که چند تا کبوتر عاشق اومدن
and swept it all away when I wasn't looking.
و همه چيز رو بردن جلوي چشمام
Wait.
صبر کن
What! What do you want?
چي چي مي خواي؟
I don't know, okay?
نمي دونم باشه؟
I don't want some open relationship like...
من يه ارتباط باز مثل
all the gay couples I know.
همه اون زوجهاي هم جنس باز که مي شناسم نمي خوام
I don't want some, some gay version of the straight couples I see!
من يه سري ، يه سري کارا رو مثل بقيه کسايي که مي بينم نمي خوام
I don't see what I want anywhere.
من چيزي رو که مي خوام هيچ جايي نمي بينم
Then just see me.
پس حالا به من نگاه کن
You know we're just us, we're not gay or straight...
مي دوني که ما مائيم. هيچ چيز ديگه اي نيستيم
or Julia or Meg, we're just two people...
جوليا يا مگ ما فقط دو تا آدميم
Adam and Steve.
آدام و اسميت
Maybe we should just accept the fact that neither of those...
شايد بايد اين واقعيت رو بپذيريم که هيچ کدوم از اون
people are relationship material.
مردم در ارتباط با هم  نيستن
That... they're both too damaged.
اينکه هر دوتاشون خيلي آسيب ديدن
We're in our thirties, of course we're damaged.
ما تو سي سالگيمون هستيم معلومه که ضربه خورديم
And you know what? I am tired.
مي دوني چيه؟ خسته شدم
I am tired of fighting you and the whole world just so...
خسته شدم از دعوا کردن باهات و همه دنيا هم همين طور
I could have something as radical and subversive...
مي تونم يه چيزي خيلي بهتر و مهم تر از يه
as a fucking boyfriend.
دوست پسر لعنتي داشته باشم
Fuck you, Steve!
لعنت به تو استيو
I may be damaged goods but I am goods nonetheless.
من ممکنه که ضربه خورده باشم ولي ضربه نميزنم
It's not my fault!
تقصير من نيست
You wouldn't understand, she's a woman, they have their ways!
تو نمي فهمي اون يه زنه اونا راه خودشون رو دارن
What, she hypnotized you with her feminine wiles?
چي! اون تو رو با حقه هاي زنونه هيپنوتيزم کرده
Yes, yes, yes she did, she did actually!
آره آره آره واقعا اين کارو کرده
What?
چي؟
What was I supposed to do, Michael?
من مي خواستم چيکار کنم مايکل؟
Every time he went to an AA meeting, I'd feel guilty.
هر دفعه که مي رفت به جلسات اي اي حسوديم مي شد
Every time I used the bathroom he'd stare at me...
هر دفعه که مي رفتم حموم بهم خيره مي شد
with a knowing look on his face.
با يه نگاه آگاهانه
Get over yourself!
چي داري مي گي
The guy saw you take a dump.
يارو تو رو ديده که رفتي حموم
You'd eventually start changing each other's diapers anyway.
خوبه کم کم شروع نکرديد کهنه ي همديگه رو عوض کنيد
No, no, this is not how it's supposed to be.
نه نه نه اونطوري که بنظر مي رسه نيست
You've got to stop with that preconceived bullshit.
بايد اين مزخرفات رو تموم کني
You guys love each other, don't you?
شماها عاشق هميد مگه نه؟
I don't even know what that means anymore.
ديگه حتي نمي دونم عشق يعني چي
Fags!
مسخره اس
God made Adam and Eve, not Adam and Steve!
خدا آدم و حوا رو خلق کرد نه آدم و استيو رو
Where, are you go...
کجا داري مي...
There you go, guys.
شما اينجا باشيد
I've got to go get limes honey, I'll be right back.
مي رم ليمو ها رو بيارم برمي گردم عزيزم
You don't get much-a nothing unless you give it a try.
# You don't get much-a nothing unless you give it a try. #
Rock the world a little, get the thunder clapping.
# Rock the world a little, get the thunder clapping. #
March yourself over there and make things happen.
# March yourself over there and make things happen. #
Give yourself a gift you can use.
# Give yourself a gift you can use. #
What the hell have you got to lose?
# What the hell have you got to lose? #
We're really all just walking in each other's shoes.
# We're really all just walking in each other's shoes. #
Step one; look. Two; smile.
# Step one; look. Two; smile. #
Three; say 'Hi'.
# Three; say 'Hi'. #
Say 'Hi'!
# Say 'Hi'! #
Hi.
سلام
This is Charlie, he uh...
اين چارليه اون...
he lives across the street from me.
اون خونه روبروي من مي شينه
Hi.
سلام
Go ahead.
برو جلو
Ask him.
ازش بخواه
What's your name?
اسمت چيه؟
Adam.
آدام
What's mine?
اسم من چيه؟
Steve.
استيو
That's right Steve, Adam and Steve.
درسته استيو آدام و استيو
So see you were wrong.
پس ببين که اشتباه مي کردي
God did make Adam and Steve because here we are.
خدا آدام و استيو رو براي هم ساخت چون حالا ما اينجائيم
Tell him, huh, tell him.
بهش بگو
Steve is sorry for the way he treated you,
استيو براي رفتاري که باهات داشته معذرت مي خواد
he's sorry about everything.
از بابت همه چيز پشيمونه
Well, I accept his apology.
خب معذرت خواهي اش رو مي پذيرم
And...
و
I'm sorry I yelled at you,
معذرت مي خوام که سرت داد کشيدم
called you cornholers in front of his parents.
جلوي خانواده ات بهت توهين کردم
Okay.
باشه
What else, what else!
ديگه چي ديگه چي
He wants to ask you for your hand...
اون مي خواد ازت بخواد که دستت رو بدي بهش
in one of them gay marriages.
تو يکي از اون ازدواج هاي هم جنس ها
A man marrying a man, that's kind of gross.
يه مرد با يه مرد ازدواج کنه يه جورايي چندش آوره
I know.
مي دونم
Well you tell him that personally I don't really...
خب تو بهش بگو که شخصا خيلي
believe in marriage and I don't really know...
به ازدواج ايمان ندارم واقعا نمي دونم
if I really believe in him anymore.
که هنوز باورش دارم يا نه
Whoa, that's harsh!
واي سنگدليه
Adam, please.
آدام خواهش مي کنم
I can't.
نمي تونم
Adam.
آدام
I choose you, I choose you.
من تو رو انتخاب کردم
I don't know why you would.
نمي دونم چرا اينکارو مي کني
Perhaps I had a wicked childhood.
# Perhaps I had a wicked childhood. #
Perhaps I had a miserable youth.
# Perhaps I had a miserable youth. #
But somewhere in my wicked, miserable past,
# But somewhere in my wicked, miserable past, #
there must have been a moment of truth.
# there must have been a moment of truth. #
For here you are, standing there, loving me.
# For here you are, standing there, loving me. #
Whether or not you should.
# Whether or not you should. #
So somewhere in my youth, or childhood.
# So somewhere in my youth, or childhood. #
I must have done something good.
# I must have done something good. #
Nothing comes from nothing, nothing ever could.
# Nothing comes from nothing, nothing ever could. #
So somewhere in my youth or childhood,
# So somewhere in my youth or childhood, #
I must have done something good.
# I must have done something good. #
Beloved family and friends at this time...
خانواده دوست داشتني و دوستان عزيز حالا...
in the wedding we do the ring ceremony.
در عروسي مراسم حلقه دادن داريم
Rhonda if you would give me Adam's ring for Steve.
روندا لطفا حلقه آدام رو بهم بده
Thank you.
ممنون
Michael if you would give me Steve's ring for Adam.
مايکل لطفا حلقه استيو رو بده
Hold hands.
دستاتون روبه هم بديد
Father Mother God we ask just now for your blessing...
پدر مادر خدا از شما الان  مي خوايم که دعا کنيد
on these beautiful wedding rings...
با اين حلقه هاي زيباي ازدواج
that they may symbolize for Adam and Steve...
که اونا نشانه اي از استيو و آدام هستن
in their union health and happiness, strength and courage,
در سلامتي واحد و شادي و قدرت و تلاش
joy and peace, abundance and prosperity,
سرور و آشتي
and unconditional loving for each other.
و عشق ورزيدن به هم ديگر تا هميشه
So be it.
پس آغاز مي کنيم
Adam if you would place this ring on Steven's hand...
آدام اگه اين حلقه رو در دست استيو بذاري
and repeat after me.
بعد از من تکرار کن
Steve, with this ring I thee wed.
استيو با اين حلقه تو را به عقد در مي آورم
Steve, if you would place this ring on Adam's hand...
استيو اگه اين حلقه رو دست آدام کني
and repeat after me.
بعد از من تکرار کن
Adam, with this ring I thee wed.
آدام با اين حلقه تو رو به عقد در مي اورم
Do you Adam Bernstein take Steve Hicks...
آدام برنستين شما استيو هيکس رو مي پذيريد
to be your beloved husband?
براي شوهرت بودن؟
I do.
بله
Steve Hicks, do you take Adam Bernstein...
استيو هيکس شما آدام برنشنيت رو مي پذيريد براي...
to be your beloved husband?
براي شوهرت بودن ؟
You bet your ass I do.
شرط مي بندم که هستم
And now by the power vested in me by the state of New York,
و حالا با قدرتي که به من  در ايالت نيويورک محول شده
I now pronounce you husband and husband.
شما رو شوهر و شوهر معرفي مي کنم
You may kiss your beloved.
مي توني معشوقه ات رو ببوسي
And now Adam in the tradition of your family,
حالا آدام به رسم خانوادگي تون
we'll break the glass.
شيشه رو مي شکونيم
Mazoltov!
مازاتوف
Love is real.
# Love is real. #
Real is love.
# Real is love. #
Love is feeling,
# Love is feeling, #
#feeling love.
#feeling love. #
Love is wanting,
# Love is wanting, #
to be loved.
# to be loved. #
Love is touch.
# Love is touch. #
Touch is love.
# Touch is love. #
Love is reaching,
# Love is reaching, #
reaching love.
# reaching love. #
Love is asking,
# Love is asking, #
to be loved.
# to be loved. #
Well...
# Well... #
you're walking down the street happy as a pig in mud.
# you're walking down the street happy as a pig in mud. #
Feeling simple and sweet...
# Feeling simple and sweet... #
like a heifer chewing her cud.
# like a heifer chewing her cud. #
Now I don't want to burst your bubble...
# Now I don't want to burst your bubble... #
and make you fret.
# and make you fret. #
But I think that I smell trouble so watch your step.
# But I think that I smell trouble so watch your step. #
If you're raring to go and hopping back in the saddle.
# If you're raring to go and hopping back in the saddle. #
Next thing you know up a creek without a paddle.
# Next thing you know up a creek without a paddle. #
If you think you want success and all its trappings.
# If you think you want success and all its trappings. #
But honey, life's a mess, shit happens.
# But honey, life's a mess, shit happens.
They say that a life is just a bowl of cherries.
# They say that a life is just a bowl of cherries. #
But they don't make greeting cards...
# But they don't make greeting cards... #
about dingleberries.
# about dingleberries. #
Now you're embarrassed and you won't let no one see you,
# Now you're embarrassed and you won't let no one see you, #
'cause they don't write love songs about diarrhea.
# 'cause they don't write love songs about diarrhea. #
You've got a foot in tomorrow and foot in yesterday.
# You've got a foot in tomorrow and foot in yesterday. #
You'll get nothing but sorrow...
# You'll get nothing but sorrow... #
cause you're crapping on today.
# cause you're crapping on today. #
No matter what, you go to keep on laughing.
# No matter what, you go to keep on laughing. #
Just laugh with your mouth shut, cause shit happens.
# Just laugh with your mouth shut, cause shit happens. #
You doing in it and you're barefoot stepping in it.
# You doing in it and you're barefoot stepping in it. #
Thinking got a master plan,
# Thinking got a master plan, #
then it all just hits the fan.
# then it all just hits the fan. #
Life can throw you for a loop.
# Life can throw you for a loop. #
Then it covers you in poop.
# Then it covers you in poop. #
Shit happens.
# Shit happens. Shit happens. #
You ain't listening to me,
# You ain't listening to me, #
then my gums are just flapping.
# then my gums are just flapping. #
The moral of this story, shit happens.
# The moral of this story, shit happens. #
What?
# What? #
Shit!
# Shit! #
Huh?
# Huh? #
Can't hear you.
# Can't hear you. #
Shit!
# Shit! #
Shit, shit, shit, shit, shit!
# Shit, shit, shit, shit, shit! #
Life's a game and you can win it even when you're knee deep in it.
# Life's a game and you can win it even when you're knee deep in it. #
Keep a fighting and scrappin'...
# Keep a fighting and scrappin'... #
cause its spraying and splattin'.
# cause its spraying and splattin'. #
Shit happens.
# Shit happens. #
Shit!
# Shit! #